<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2022 on Alicia Guo</title>
    <link>https://axguo.github.io/tags/2022/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2022 on Alicia Guo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://axguo.github.io/tags/2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>life&#39;s little gifts 🍃</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/lifesgifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/lifesgifts/</guid>
      <description>from life to me to you :)
 1-29-23  Unconference. Next time I will run a session/conversation.   1-28-23  Have you ever held an idea in your mind and tried to write it without words? I&amp;rsquo;m going further off the abstract deep end with asemic writing.   1-25-23  I NOW HAVE A VINTAGE CORONA FOUR TYPEWRITER. To feel the physicality of my typing like this is incredible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>finding the right words</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/feb22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/feb22/</guid>
      <description>january 2022 - february 2022
I think about this quote (outside of any context) a lot1.
 “Have you, dear reader, ever tried writing poetry that will set the collective soul of your nation on fire? If no, why not?”
 3-1-22
Lately it’s been hard to think - running from city to city and studio to classroom - I’m forgetting to feel the snow crunch beneath my feet and to take my mask off to smell the fresh air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>what I know to be true [22]</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/other/whatiknow22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/other/whatiknow22/</guid>
      <description>What I know to be true at 22, and possibly not at 23.
What I know changes with each of the lives that I live.
I think it&amp;rsquo;d be fun to do one of these every year :)
  What I know to be true is that attention and observation are what make life meaningful. I want to witness the world and the people in it. Attending to myself, to friends, to nature, to strangers has never been more pressing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
