<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Misc on Alicia Guo</title>
    <link>https://axguo.github.io/categories/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Misc on Alicia Guo</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://axguo.github.io/categories/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>things that are slow and sticky</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/slow-sticky/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/slow-sticky/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Memory&amp;rsquo;s images, once they are fixed in words, are erased&amp;quot; - Italo Calvino, Invisible Cities&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;i&#34;&gt;I. &lt;a href=&#34;#i&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;6 parts titanium white, 3 parts phthalo blue, 1 part ultramarine blue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;a hint of napthol red and ochre yellow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;a sky that bleeds saying goodbye&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;to a sun too quickly burning away&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Walnuts can break a man, or at least they broke me. What other nut can be sold encased in an indestructible shell, cutting the hands of an eight year old determined to prove her strength? What need does a bitter and oily nut have to be so guarded, only to be spat and not swallowed by a girl determined to memorize the folds that make it distinct from a pecan so that she may learn who to avoid. In a steady machine, the outer hull is rotated while slashed until metal bristles rub off the first layer, before moving to cracking the shells. A naked walnut can be sold as is, or pressed and crushed and pressed again into a paste. An oil is then freed. The startling flavor created from a violent process makes it perfect for drizzling over salads or complimenting desserts. The pale richness also makes it a prime candidate for a medium to smooth out oil paints.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Dine Alone</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You try to catch the waiter’s attention, but his focus skips over to the young couple by the window. They have just sat down, but there is twice the body to catch the eye — twice the hunger, twice the urgency. You give a small wave as he passes by, not enough for a friend, barely enough for the stranger. There is no need to be extravagant, no one is watching — movement from a still corner will always elicit surprise. There is not much room for back and forth, dishes are not to be shared. No commitment issues, the item you choose is what you’ll get. It all happens very fast -  silent conversations always pass the quickest. You are decisive, you have decided to be a party of one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
