<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>learning on Alicia Guo</title>
    <link>https://axguo.github.io/tags/learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in learning on Alicia Guo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://axguo.github.io/tags/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>steal like an artist</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/steal-like-an-artist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/steal-like-an-artist/</guid>
      <description>Steal like an artist is one of my favorite phrases to whisper to myself when I am sitting with indecision over a new project, to say that copying can lead to imitation which can lead to emulation and there is where new art is born. Stealing like an artist means being able to stitch together faint whiffs of past lives into new ones. It seems to me that there are two ways to begin at something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>anyone can be a dancer</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/anyone_can_be_a_dancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/anyone_can_be_a_dancer/</guid>
      <description>A friend once told me that there must be something special about human faces that makes them so hard to draw — a certain elusive quality that comes from the ineffable experience of being human. This took me by surprise because I live with an extremely strong belief that it only takes practice, and relatively little at that, to obtain the skills necessary to draw a reasonable human face. It’s true that most attempts at facial features are awful, more resembling elongated emojis than facial features but I think that’s only because we take our faces for granted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I can do it, painfully</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/do-it-painfully/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/do-it-painfully/</guid>
      <description>Something wonderful has changed here. I feel so full of ideas, sending out pitches instead of finished work. Today I reached out to strangers (non-coders) asking if they wanted to collaborate on unspecified projects without knowing if I’d be able to help bring us to reach a shared vision. I felt giddy and sophisticated, like an artist about to graduate from faking it to making it.
A year ago I would have balked at the thought of offering to create something seemingly magical and impossible without a hint of a plan.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
