<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alicia Guo</title>
    <link>https://axguo.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alicia Guo</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://axguo.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Woven Poem</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/woven-poem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/woven-poem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An interactive installation that asks viewers to participate in collaboratively weaving and un-weaving a poem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;video class=&#34;tint&#34; muted=&#34;true&#34; loop autoplay playsinline style=&#34;width: 100%&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;source src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/woven_poem/woven_timelapse.MOV&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34; /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/video&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;&#xA;An interactive installation. Viewers could print out and take home the poems they made with Found Poem.&#xA;    &lt;section class=&#34;gen-gallery&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/woven_poem/woven2.JPG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/woven_poem/woven3.jpeg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/woven_poem/woven4.JPG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/woven_poem/woven_timelapse.MOV&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>things I do daily [live]</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/daily/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/daily/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are the things I&amp;rsquo;ve committed to or keep coming back to. I wonder if these distract from bigger projects, after all, if I keep adding these small dailies my todos will eventually be filled but as for now I will keep these that bring me joy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aliciaguo.com/morning-pages/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;morning pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: 3 page stream of consciousness journaling in the mornings&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/patchwork.letters/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;painting a snippet of the sky&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: the gray weather depressed me so I decided to paint it every day. now I notice so much in the sky that I&amp;rsquo;m endlessly fascinated regardless of the weather.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vShqauv5ofA0p5P-v_X-UnV4MlW9fudWjCu-VLTyNuV4dNIsScjZ6zB4HOLahLTtQ_WRRjUWNwwVkzn/pubhtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a poem a day keeps the blues at bay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: it&amp;rsquo;s surprising how much five minutes a day can ground me.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20 min dance session at night&lt;/strong&gt;: I wiggle and wave like a crazy person before I sleep. this is a pillar of my happiness.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;seasonal&#34;&gt;seasonal &lt;a href=&#34;#seasonal&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hyperlink.academy/s/mangotango/s/77pAGMrlZ2JMZgde4Zr6Ov/paper%20%26%20thread&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;paper &amp;amp; thread [march 2024]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: daily handmade projects on Hyperlink Academy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023: some world expanding moments</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/world-expanding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/world-expanding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style&gt;#single {font-family: &#34;Spectral&#34;, serif; font-weight: 300; font-size: 1.2em;}&lt;/style&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The phrase I keep coming back to this year is ✨ &lt;em&gt;world-expanding.&lt;/em&gt; ✨ It applies to experiences, cities, people, and even the sky. When I see someone do that crazy something/live in a way that I didn’t even know was possible, it feels like my world has expanded: the possibility space for living has just grown that much bigger. &#xA;&#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;sidenote-number&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;small class=&#34;sidenote&#34;&gt;&#xA;    This was written as a letter to a small group of friends but I wanted to share. Original doc &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/117GOj73CKeGTEwQpYVC51YTQec10_GnwYUqF9oU8iPA/edit?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &#xA;  &lt;/small&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>James Turrell</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/turrell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/turrell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been over a week and I’m still thinking about James Turrell. The feeling of being in that room and seeing infinite space within the bounds that I know exist. The glow of the lights. The smoothness. The not knowing. The ethereal effect his pieces have with light sneaks into my thoughts in the form of questions. I remember standing in that room and wondering if my art could ever make someone feel like this. What materials can I use? What technologies are still mysterious enough to elicit wonder through not knowing how they work? What was most fun was trying to reverse engineer his effects with friends. What direction can I explore deeply enough in? What group of people can I find? Turrell had a group to experiment with. I love that with Turrell’s works I feel like I could sit there for hours &amp;ndash; it’s a feeling I actively seek to foster in my web-based pieces, and something I only just now realized I could aim for in real life too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIT Showcase</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/mit-showcase/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/mit-showcase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;&#xA;An interactive installation. Viewers could print out and take home the poems they made with Found Poem.&#xA;    &lt;section class=&#34;gen-gallery&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/events/mit/display.jpeg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/events/mit/display2.png&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/events/mit/display3.png&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/events/mit/print.png&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes On Love</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/notes-on-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/notes-on-love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;&#xA;A meditation on love. In collaboration with Harvard Conflux group. &#xA;    &lt;section class=&#34;gen-gallery&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/events/love/1.jpeg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/events/love/2.jpeg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/events/love/3.jpeg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/events/love/4.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some things to be</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/to-be-something/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/to-be-something/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;were not meant to be. I wish&lt;br&gt;&#xA;to be lucky, enough&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;for the red I am wearing.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To be formless, genreless. Miscellaneous&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;always. To be willingly&lt;br&gt;&#xA;categorized. I give you consent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To be occasionally refreshing.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To be a factory of permissions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To be a stronger vessel for my heart.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To be next.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>reflections from a month(ish) of generative sketches</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/genuary23-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/genuary23-reflections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aliciaguo.com/genuary2023/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;sketches&lt;/a&gt; :)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some thoughts on a month(ish) of generative sketches. &#xA;&#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;sidenote-number&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;small class=&#34;sidenote&#34;&gt;&#xA;    I hesitate to use the word “generative” anymore because it’s been so overtaken by AI. What I mean here for my works are good old creative coding sketches, turtle graphics vibes and shaders. Pixels that have been handcrafted with care.&#xA;  &lt;/small&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA; Pretty informal compared to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aliciaguo.com/posts/dailysketch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;post last year&lt;/a&gt; and more of a collection of floating thoughts varying in importance to see if the challenge is worth doing again next year and in what capacity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Be a Poem</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/to-be-a-poem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/to-be-a-poem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;column1&#34;&gt;&#xA;    View the endless poem &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aliciaguo.com/to-be/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;mark&gt;here.&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;An exploration on things to be.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;    &lt;p&gt;Inspired by Chen Chen&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/143241/when-i-grow-up-i-want-to-be-a-list-of-further-possibilities&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;When I Grow Up I Want to Be a List of Further Possibilities.&lt;/a&gt; I love the use of &#34;to be&#34; as a yearning and exploration. Created with Rita.js and context-free grammars.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tobeabot&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;mark&gt;bot&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aliciaguo.com/posts/to-be-something/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;mark&gt;poem&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; too :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;column1&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;video class=&#34;tint&#34; muted=&#34;true&#34; loop autoplay playsinline style=&#34;width: 100%&#34;&gt;&#xA;                &lt;source&#xA;                  src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/to_be/demo.mp4&#34;&#xA;                  type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&#xA;                /&gt;&#xA;              &lt;/video&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>steal like an artist</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/steal-like-an-artist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/steal-like-an-artist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steal like an artist&lt;/em&gt; is one of my favorite phrases to whisper to myself when I am sitting with indecision over a new project, to say that copying can lead to imitation which can lead to emulation and there is where new art is born. Stealing like an artist means being able to stitch together faint whiffs of past lives into new ones. It seems to me that there are two ways to begin at something. Either being a direct student (ex: following tutorials) or copying (attempting to recreate). The best curriculum is a combination of both and I’m thankful for my first creative coding class taught by Zach Lieberman (amazing artist and prof!) called Recreating the Past. Our whole class was focused on examining artists’ past works and selecting a few to code up while giving us the general tools to do so. These art pieces we tried to recreate consisted not just of digital artifacts, but animations, interactive installations, sketches, and textiles. It was a blessing to be given the permission to forget trying to be original in content and focus on the process. The destination was given and we were tasked with mapping out the journey and oddly enough there was a feeling of something resembling originality in this piecing together of existing work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>uneven seasonings</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/uneven_seasoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/uneven_seasoning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been cooking a lot recently and trying to find my way to being a capital C chef, the ones that are able to commune with their ingredients and just know which ones will be compatible and have that intuition for what proportions to include. I’m trying to find the secret sauce. The Food Lab by Kenji López-Alt sits on my shelf largely ignored for now due to my stubborn trial and error mindset wanting to develop this relationship naturally. In short, I’m reinventing the wheel. Maybe most of the reason I haven’t gotten around to the book is it is big and intimidating and I was lazy. But I love watching Food Wars while I cook — it’s an entire anime dedicated to discovering food through exploration, trying and failing and stuffed with so many mouth watering animations that make me sad knowing that real food will never look as appetizing. I’m motivated and inspired to be adventurous with my recipes. I want to make them mine, to cross over into the realm of food as art. The episodes are also full of food science and molecular gastronomy to varying degrees of exaggeration and accuracy where my fact check consists not of google but just just trying the thing. One of the plot-twisting moments comes from using uneven flavors — spreading seasoning in varying areas and concentrations over a smooth uniform distribution — to enhance taste. Each bite becomes a surprise, a shifting dance of unexpected flavors and avoids becoming one dimensional. I haven’t tested this fully - it certainly is true for sauces: drizzling and dipping often taste better than dousing a food in sauce. This also checks out with most of the recipes I’ve read and watched. Salt/oil/seasonings are sprinkled on haphazardly and for many years I wondered why they weren’t mixed or massaged better as to be more uniform. Whenever I would, I’d discover that it clearly did not taste as good.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>anyone can be a dancer</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/anyone_can_be_a_dancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/anyone_can_be_a_dancer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A friend once told me that there must be something special about human faces that makes them so hard to draw — a certain elusive quality that comes from the ineffable experience of being human. This took me by surprise because I live with an extremely strong belief that it only takes practice, and relatively little at that, to obtain the skills necessary to draw a reasonable human face. It’s true that most attempts at facial features are awful, more resembling elongated emojis than facial features but I think that’s only because we take our faces for granted. How often do we really notice individual shapes that make up our face, the new freckles from the sun or the path of wrinkles that surface from a smile? Can you conjure up the contours of your friend’s face the same way you can a rolling chair or a head of broccoli? It’s impossible to draw what you can’t see. One of my favorite classes in undergrad was a studio drawing class, and within the first two classes totalling six hours students went from alien scribbles to stunningly accurate sketches. It was one of the most formative “you can do anything with enough practice” lessons I witnessed. The difference was that they weren’t engaging in brute forcing their practice. Our prof consistently stressed attention to detail and often would ask us to verbalize our observations when things seemed off, making them easier to translate to paper. The results were by no means close to photographic, but in a way they were better. There was a raw charm to the character imbued by the individual artists who had learned to direct their observations but had not yet succumbed to paralyzing intense scrutinizing of their own work. So, yes, I believe that anyone can learn to draw a face within a day with the right instruction. Today I told a dancer that I’m not great at dancing (though I do enjoy it) and she responded with the good old “anyone can learn to dance with enough practice!” And it hit me that she probably sees dance the same way I see art. The trick to leveling up fast in drawing is to learn how to observe. I wonder what is for dance (I’m going to ask next time I see her) and what it is for all of the other areas of study, the ones that can be practiced. I&amp;rsquo;m grateful that I can understand this deeply through art. I imagine it takes a bit more time for a subject such as physics or glassblowing. The seed to be an artist is something that everyone has been doing to different degrees their entire lives! We observe so many details every single day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I can do it, painfully</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/do-it-painfully/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/do-it-painfully/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Something wonderful has changed here. I feel so full of ideas, sending out pitches instead of finished work. Today I reached out to strangers (non-coders) asking if they wanted to collaborate on unspecified projects without knowing if I’d be able to help bring us to reach a shared vision. I felt giddy and sophisticated, like an artist about to graduate from faking it to making it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A year ago I would have balked at the thought of offering to create something seemingly magical and impossible without a hint of a plan. I had just as many ideas, less formed, more wobbly and ungrounded, floating within the realm of &lt;a href=&#34;https://autotranslucence.wordpress.com/2018/03/30/becoming-a-magician/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;magicians&lt;/a&gt;. A pitch was a proposal and a promise. A promise to deliver if chosen and I didn’t think I could. I’ve learned a few things since then, have since learned to have confidence in myself that &lt;em&gt;I can figure it out, though maybe with a lot of pain.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genuary 2023</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/genuary23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/genuary23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;column1&#34;&gt;&#xA;        View all sketches &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aliciaguo.com/genuary2023/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;mark&gt;here.&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;        &lt;!-- See my &lt;a href=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/posts/dailysketch&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;mark&gt; blog post&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; about the process of making these daily sketches. --&gt;&#xA;        Reflection post coming soon. &#xA;        &lt;p&gt;Daily creative sketches made using p5js following the prompts for January 2023. The focus for this month was learning and developing sketches to turn into larger art pieces later. You can play with them and re-generate your own unique sketch! &#xA;        &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;column2 small-column&#34;&gt;&#xA;        some favorites (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aliciaguo.com/genuary2023/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt;check out the rest!&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&#xA;        &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&#xA;        parametric blooms&#xA;        &lt;video class=&#34;tint&#34; muted=&#34;true&#34; loop autoplay playsinline style=&#34;width: 100%&#34;&gt;&#xA;                &lt;source&#xA;                  src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/genuary23/sketch4.mp4&#34;&#xA;                  type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&#xA;                /&gt;&#xA;              &lt;/video&gt;&#xA;        more moiré&#xA;        &lt;video class=&#34;tint&#34; muted=&#34;true&#34; loop autoplay playsinline style=&#34;width: 100%&#34;&gt;&#xA;                &lt;source&#xA;                  src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/genuary23/sketch3.mp4&#34;&#xA;                  type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&#xA;                /&gt;&#xA;              &lt;/video&gt;&#xA;        drunk thumbprint&#xA;        &lt;video class=&#34;tint&#34; muted=&#34;true&#34; loop autoplay playsinline style=&#34;width: 100%&#34;&gt;&#xA;                &lt;source&#xA;                  src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/genuary23/sketch2.mp4&#34;&#xA;                  type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&#xA;                /&gt;&#xA;              &lt;/video&gt;&#xA;        wonderland&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/genuary23/download3.png&#34;  alt=&#34;the words abide by quick jiving memories reflected down repeatedly where occasionally individual letters are replaced with similar letters&#34;/&gt;&#xA;        colored contacts&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/genuary23/sketch.gif&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts from a dying mall</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dying-mall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dying-mall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wake up today feeling the vulnerability of winter. Fall leaves falling, leaving me exposed like every year before. Cold air rushing in the change of seasons and time running out, running towards an arbitrary new year, running towards made up deadlines. The ground becomes too stiff to bury old pictures, so I hang onto them in pockets that won’t fit more than half a person. I see my wishes being stripped naked like the orange trees that line the streets in a direction picked with a roll of the dice. Follow the dots blindly walk through indiscriminate gales that threaten to question my loves until I reach a dried out beacon. Every town has one. Jewelry kiosks and outdated clothes. Panda Express and fortune cookies smell like safety, of childhood before seasons and summers playing chess and watching Goosebumps while the knights and rooks took their break. Can’t watch Goosebumps anymore, not since learning monsters are real. Fall has been breaking this place for far too long, stripping the dreams of a common space now crowded out by commercial suburbia.  This one’s third floor, closest to a ceiling wide skylight: already shut down, gates down. Second floor fighting to hold onto customers that never make it past the first. If this is trickle-down theory from heaven then hell might be the last safe place. Crack the cookie to read the slip of paper that falls out. That future has already passed:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I practice whispering</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/i-practice-whispering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/i-practice-whispering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Crawling earthquakes are born of a thousand&lt;br&gt;&#xA;whispered truths. Picking out crimson apricots,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;bruising soft stones with my thumb.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Walking down stiff concrete streets&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;peeking around corners, wondering if a impish wind&lt;br&gt;&#xA;has curved my words. If anyone can hear a daring&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;breath, humming lyrics never to be shared. I practice&lt;br&gt;&#xA;singing in an empty parking lot—there is a dandelion&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;gathering his friends. I practice driving through&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the same cracked road you first showed me. I practice&lt;br&gt;&#xA;circling the roundabout and I keep&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>a wish from the heart’s left ventricle</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/wish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/wish/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;back to the building from three years ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;sneaking in to the rhythm of the concierge’s nods.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I keep finding myself in places I know too well,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;an overexposed photo of blurred bodies yet&lt;br&gt;&#xA;my face sits clearly where it has always been&lt;br&gt;&#xA;near new students that have learned to carry&lt;br&gt;&#xA;their name tags in their mouths. the pink touch-me-nots&lt;br&gt;&#xA;beg to be saved from the coming winter so I pluck&lt;br&gt;&#xA;one to dry with heavy words and strangers&lt;br&gt;&#xA;identify her as patience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>planting permission</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/planting-permission/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/planting-permission/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/posts/swiss_mountain.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;view of the swiss mountains&#34; style=&#34;width: 60%;&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I love the mountains here because there are always dense collections of wildflowers under the tree line: purple buds sitting in crevices and yellow petals caressing their grassy neighbors. In places their beauty rivals the alps, the colorful fields an undeniable testimony to the power of nature undisturbed and to the charm of small wonders. They sway in the wind with a carefree attitude of the unbothered and unnamed, some immortalized and dried out by the sun. A few are now resting pressed in my notebook. I try to search for their names. I can’t find any—in another life, one not so forgiving, they would have been known as weeds. White puffballs are the most abundant amongst these mountainside stems, holding globes of dandelion seeds resting half undressed. Dandelions were once celebrated in magic and medicine. Now they’re relentlessly eradicated from lawns and city grass.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>what if writing was...</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/writing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-map&#34;&gt;a map &lt;a href=&#34;#a-map&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To begin with intentions is terribly important — by setting intentions for my writing, I see myself as marking the landscapes and the boundaries of the territory that I am embarking into. To set my intentions is to attempt to create the map of my mind as I know it now — undoubtedly incomplete and fated to be rearranged and re-rearranged, but it will be a starting point because no one begins with a blank map. We all have copied bits and pieces from others, imitating and making up geographies from everyone we have ever met or read. The making of my map consists of conversations under late night kitchen lights describing the contours of a road that resembles friendship and opinions passed around through so many mouths that I wonder if the shape of the conclusion I have received on some political matter that I know nothing about even resembles the original. It feels like playing a long game of picture telephone, passing pieces of drawings around to be mimicked where the entire world is participating and the end result is something horrifically, comically inaccurate and distorted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cal Anderson</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/cal-anderson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/cal-anderson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;an irrational ratio&lt;br&gt;&#xA;each hour spent at the park&lt;br&gt;&#xA;parked outside the bookstore that&lt;br&gt;&#xA;we never entered, spend an hour&lt;br&gt;&#xA;on the phone, conveying a&lt;br&gt;&#xA;secondhand kind of love to my&lt;br&gt;&#xA;friend who hasn’t heard this&lt;br&gt;&#xA;smile in my voice, it’s been so long&lt;br&gt;&#xA;no body should ever be that warm&lt;br&gt;&#xA;i might burn from the flutter of my legs&lt;br&gt;&#xA;doing a silly dance, the audience gone&lt;br&gt;&#xA;the performance is over but you are still here&lt;br&gt;&#xA;making a fool out of my unavailability&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and i bow into a hug that doesn’t quite fit&lt;br&gt;&#xA;yet fingers creep in the grass, faster than&lt;br&gt;&#xA;the recognition of comfort and seeing myself&lt;br&gt;&#xA;in your eyes, a little too close&lt;br&gt;&#xA;a little too familiar&lt;br&gt;&#xA;i’m so used to you, it’s been so long&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gut Feelings</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/gut-feelings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/gut-feelings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If I trust my head. Twisted&lt;br&gt;&#xA;vines creep to an unreachable&lt;br&gt;&#xA;sun but knowledge sits in roots&lt;br&gt;&#xA;tangled, knotted in biased hugs.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Amber words dissolve in a salty&lt;br&gt;&#xA;river where flames steal my bark&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and flesh. I swing between birds,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;or are they stationary fish? See&lt;br&gt;&#xA;my body lost in glass ferns,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;too fragile to free.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If I trust my heart. Violent&lt;br&gt;&#xA;spirits shake yellow chrysanthemums&lt;br&gt;&#xA;growing from my chest. Soft painted&lt;br&gt;&#xA;jealousy flirts with earnest rage. I bow&lt;br&gt;&#xA;to reason without a compass — east&lt;br&gt;&#xA;knows no submission. I try to lose&lt;br&gt;&#xA;myself in hopeless desire&lt;br&gt;&#xA;already lost in autumn showers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>conversations in the dark</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/conversations-in-the-dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/conversations-in-the-dark/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/posts/nico.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;painting of a colorful city of lights on a hill at night&#34; style=&#34;width: 49%;&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;img-caption&#34; style=&#34;width: 49%;&#34;&gt;Mi Pequeno San Juan by Nico Thomassin: I first saw this painting in a gallery in Puerto Rico and it forever will capture my feeling of awe to witness a whole city glow at night&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m laughing and cradling my knees while the moon rises over a sun that has not yet said goodbye. It is an impossibly charming outlook of the entire city of Zürich from this rooftop that somehow is just taller than its neighbors but I still find myself looking forward to the ample clouds that pass by to cover the roundness of the moonlight. Because in the dark, I stop caring about most things. I can feel my face relax, free to move into configurations that no one will see, unburdened by the weight of a smile that always lasts too long. My body reacts in ways unchecked with loose chuckles and shifts of surprise. No one can see me, or so I’d like to believe. What exists in the dark is only the floating voices and a heightened perception of how I feel, and in this moment I am happy. Happy to feel so comfortable sitting around cold pizza with new friends on top of a whole city and happy that silent pauses feel less heavy in the dark. I could close my eyes and hear the exclamations around me and pick out each unique laugh. The absence of light is a blessing for someone who sometimes overthinks, attuned to the minuscule shifts in another’s demeanor. It’s no wonder that some of my favorite conversations have happened at night: lying on the pier under the stars and spilling out our heartaches, jokes on a dark park bench, or conversations like this, where daylight faded and we decided to stay. I think it’s the same reason why I prefer phone calls to video chat: when everything else is stripped away except voice, we fill up the space in a raw, unfiltered way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>things that are slow and sticky</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/slow-sticky/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/slow-sticky/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Memory&amp;rsquo;s images, once they are fixed in words, are erased&amp;quot; - Italo Calvino, Invisible Cities&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;i&#34;&gt;I. &lt;a href=&#34;#i&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;6 parts titanium white, 3 parts phthalo blue, 1 part ultramarine blue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;a hint of napthol red and ochre yellow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;a sky that bleeds saying goodbye&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;to a sun too quickly burning away&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Walnuts can break a man, or at least they broke me. What other nut can be sold encased in an indestructible shell, cutting the hands of an eight year old determined to prove her strength? What need does a bitter and oily nut have to be so guarded, only to be spat and not swallowed by a girl determined to memorize the folds that make it distinct from a pecan so that she may learn who to avoid. In a steady machine, the outer hull is rotated while slashed until metal bristles rub off the first layer, before moving to cracking the shells. A naked walnut can be sold as is, or pressed and crushed and pressed again into a paste. An oil is then freed. The startling flavor created from a violent process makes it perfect for drizzling over salads or complimenting desserts. The pale richness also makes it a prime candidate for a medium to smooth out oil paints.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Dine Alone</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You try to catch the waiter’s attention, but his focus skips over to the young couple by the window. They have just sat down, but there is twice the body to catch the eye — twice the hunger, twice the urgency. You give a small wave as he passes by, not enough for a friend, barely enough for the stranger. There is no need to be extravagant, no one is watching — movement from a still corner will always elicit surprise. There is not much room for back and forth, dishes are not to be shared. No commitment issues, the item you choose is what you’ll get. It all happens very fast -  silent conversations always pass the quickest. You are decisive, you have decided to be a party of one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>life&#39;s little gifts 🍃</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/lifesgifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/lifesgifts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;from life to me to you :)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-29-23&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Unconference. Next time I will run a session/conversation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-28-23&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Have you ever held an idea in your mind and tried to write it without words? I&amp;rsquo;m going further off the abstract deep end with asemic writing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-25-23&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I NOW HAVE A VINTAGE CORONA FOUR TYPEWRITER. To feel the physicality of my typing like this is incredible.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-21-23&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grateful to be spending the first Chinese New Year at home in four years. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to be a little superstitious this year since it&amp;rsquo;s the year of the rabbit and wear red for luck. I find these traditions more and more inevitable.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;12-27-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When it&amp;rsquo;s cold in Texas all of the shrubs get blankets.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;12-25-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Being released from quarantine for the holidays is a blessing. I am so grateful for the mundane. Of being able to eat meals with my parents and coexist in the same spaces.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;4-19-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Orchid mantis! A mantis that looks like an orchid! They exist!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;4-7-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You can be a greedy reader. I’m a greedy writer.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3-19-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Feeling comfortable within a group is a gift. I feel so comfortable in my body and emotions right now.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3-13-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Erie Meyer describing how special Lina Khan is - “she’s a jelly bean!” 🥺&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3-12-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Housewarmings! Warm house. House friends. New friends. I feel warm.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3-9-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Painting through the night alone in the studio is an S tier experience. I spent three hours painting fabric with snow falling at the window and have never felt more relaxed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3-3-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I love love love small classes that turn into family. I feel so comfortable in my writing class workshopping or even just sitting and sharing hot takes. How can we support more small-scale communities like this?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-25-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;​​The spaces I occupy constantly shift into new places. Spending hours meditating on the ground with raindrop music transforms my room into a soft, glowing forest. What other spaces can I change into places?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-21-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;​​“Murder your darlings” -Sir Arthur Quiller-Couch. What a great way of phrasing advice on how to not get stuck artistically. Time to kill my darlings and move on to new creative happenings.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-19-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Started reading Mythos by Stephen Fry and I&amp;rsquo;m already very excited. The Greeks believed that began not with a god or a bang, but CHAOS.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-15-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thinking of writing not as work (which breeds reluctance) nor relaxation (a fickle association), but as &lt;em&gt;endurance&lt;/em&gt;. In the same way that running is painful and you want to die until it&amp;rsquo;s not and becomes enjoyable (at least for me), writing&amp;rsquo;s benefits are felt over time and can be difficult in the day to day.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-14-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Telescopic text!! This guy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/_jzhao/status/1493274555921674255?s=20&amp;amp;t=zpUqbdXsUVogVfFKU9-PZg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gift&lt;/a&gt; to his girlfriend is also a gift to me because I&amp;rsquo;m now PUMPED to try this new art form. Can&amp;rsquo;t wait to write some telescopic poems. This is what gets me excited about creative tools and open source.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-10-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sculpting, oil painting, frosting - there&amp;rsquo;s not much difference. Working with a thick malleable medium with a knife. It&amp;rsquo;s too easy to imagine that the paint flowers I am spreading are made of a yummy buttercream frosting.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-6-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spent a day crash coursing myself on differential equations and signal processing for a class I want to take. Fun moments like these remind me of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sive.rs/kimo#:~:text=If%20you%27re%20more%20driven,ve%20had%20no%20speed%20limit.&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;no speed limit article&lt;/a&gt; by Sivers and I should really do this more often.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-5-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Attended the symphony with my roommates and listened to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://handelandhaydn.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bach Brandenburg Concertos&lt;/a&gt;. This was my first time witnessing such an intimate concert: cozy theater, small group of musicians who stood, and no conductor! The musicians were fully together without a central metronome. Seeing the movement of each performer&amp;rsquo;s body as they swayed and danced to their own playing while passing the harmony between groups of instruments was mesmerizing. I felt like I could visualize the hopping of the melody from violins to violas to cellos. The harpsichord&amp;rsquo;s sound was a beautiful and entirely different sound from the piano I&amp;rsquo;m used to - not quite sure how to describe it. I was fully transported. The flutist was an enchantress embodying the movements from head to toe - body an extension of the instrument, moving in tandem with the violinist. I was so wowed and moved by this performance!! Live instrumental music always does something to me. So energized!!!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-2-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Seeing the form of the essay and writing in general as CARTOGRAPHY. I am mapping out uncharted ideas and editing and creating boundaries to show others.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-31-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Every year I get to have two new years :) and I think that&amp;rsquo;s wonderful.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-30-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Desire paths - &amp;ldquo;the paths that humans prefer, rather than the paths that humans create.&amp;rdquo; Snow is a great way of surfacing the true trails of human movement.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-25-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Silence in the woods and abundant stars. I&amp;rsquo;m so happy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-15-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The people we love are all somewhat figments of our imagination. Probably the most powerful moment in the Three Body Problem series for me, and so far every person I recommend the series to texts me when they reach that section.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-12-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Building worlds with speculative fiction: how, and where, do we cultivate hope? Thrilled for weekly discussions and reading more short sci-fi stories ahh.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-9-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Seeing comfort with silence as a strength.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-3-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;art papers!! are a thing!!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;12-23-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In reflecting on the amazing profs I had this past semester, I&amp;rsquo;m amazed by how passion and knowledge clearly shine through in a person&amp;rsquo;s voice. I don&amp;rsquo;t think Claire (Asian American theater prof) has ever ended up following a syllabus, but just from her conversational teachings I&amp;rsquo;ve learned so much. And even more surprisingly, I&amp;rsquo;ve retained it all with such a deep understanding. I intimately know the state of avant-garde theater in China and the historical plays and their role in politics. She once said that there are people she talks to that make her believe that theater is the most important thing one can do in the world, but that&amp;rsquo;s the way I feel when I&amp;rsquo;m in her class. I want to be able to inspire the same levels of interest. Best prof ever.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;12-18-21&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Somehow my &lt;a href=&#34;https://imageproxy.ifunny.co/crop:x-20,resize:640x,quality:90x75/images/e393def94d970356240fa374948061dccbc0f421374f76c06116d52a6d6483e8_1.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;del&gt;mom&lt;/del&gt; parents&lt;/a&gt; got me the perfect gift without me talking about the depressing weather. A therapy light (so bright!) and What I Know For Sure. Getting a gift that has so much thought and understanding leaves me fuzzy and warm inside.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;12-3-21&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kenliu.name/books/what-is-silkpunk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;silkpunk!&lt;/a&gt; technology as language!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;11-28-21&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Who is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://autotranslucence.wordpress.com/2018/03/30/becoming-a-magician/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;magician you&lt;/a&gt;? The magician me would probably have a book published and an art exhibit. I want to think bigger.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;11-20-21&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Where else except MIT is it the culture to try to find as many hidden vents and crawl spaces to claim. Next up - creating a small art gallery in a vent :)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;11-14-21&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;there&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yume_Wo_Katare&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ramen place for dreams&lt;/a&gt; - it was a gift to share in everyone&amp;rsquo;s dreams and think about mine.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;10-31-21&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the mundane, with someone we love, turns into something special and priceless&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;10-28-21&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;My dreams eerily mirror aspects of my day. Can I predict my dream&amp;rsquo;s contents?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;10-13-21&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What a wonderful feeling to be able to laugh alongside one&amp;rsquo;s fears.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;9-10-21&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vessels for love are these squishy gooey containers. They can stretch and contract. Mine has expanded the past day and I will continue to grow my capacity to hold love.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anatomy of the Collective</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/anatomy-of-the-collective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/anatomy-of-the-collective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;_1-a-branch-of-morphology-that-deals-with-the-structure-of-organisms_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;1: a branch of morphology that deals with the structure of organisms&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_1-a-branch-of-morphology-that-deals-with-the-structure-of-organisms_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;how to build a home&lt;br&gt;&#xA;of identical red scaled roofs —&lt;br&gt;&#xA;homeowner’s serpent&lt;br&gt;&#xA;      swallowing sounds&lt;br&gt;&#xA;of mismatched bricks and cartoon walls covering&lt;br&gt;&#xA;jelly beans spread on a child’s lap&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;how does she sort out the saccharine pebbles?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;      sweet ribbon scarlet&lt;br&gt;&#xA;      of a blood that pumps in her heart but&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;my blood swirls gold and green with&lt;br&gt;&#xA;a chokable envy&lt;br&gt;&#xA;for a world that regards more than&lt;br&gt;&#xA;      silky dark strands&lt;br&gt;&#xA;            strangling&lt;br&gt;&#xA;            a model esophagus&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;I cannot stay silent&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;as she pushes my burnt bones and gray lungs into opposite piles&lt;br&gt;&#xA;sinewy muscle&lt;br&gt;&#xA;      screaming&lt;br&gt;&#xA;            &amp;amp; conquered&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;it is all she has ever learned&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>explorations</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/explorations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/explorations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;_noticing_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;noticing&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_noticing_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;touch things - the leaves on the bush or the wall of the old building and really feel the interaction&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;take a walk down the street without earbuds and try to notice as many sounds as possible, there is a whole orchestra in traffic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;food meditations - appreciation for the flavors and textures before devouring&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;live life as the main character in a Studio Ghibli movie - romanticize the little things and see the wind dance joyfully through the grass&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;go on a walk - romanticize the little things, see myself as a studio ghibli movie&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;people watch or listen - eavesdropping by a better name. come up with wild stories for each human or object&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;how high is the ceiling right now?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;_living-poetically_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;living poetically&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_living-poetically_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;carry a notebook around and write/doodle all of life’s gifts&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;journal at a park&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I like parks&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;live at parks, bring a blanket and a good book&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;art museums as nourishment of the soul, not mind - focus on the feelings&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;turning spaces into new places&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;sitting at night and feeling the infinite expanse of not being able to see boundaries&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;transform spaces with music and scents&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;_art_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;art&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_art_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;gesture drawings - 30 second sketches to capture the _essence _of a person&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;blind contour drawings - don’t look at the page and release yourself from the shackles of perfection and give yourself permission to notice details&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;make rubbings of objects. touch them. feel them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;zoooooom in&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;self portraits, but make them short and interpretive&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;_writing_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;writing&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_writing_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what did you eat today? write a poem in 10 minutes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what sounds do the objects in your life make? find their rhythms - what do they sound like?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;_moving_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;moving&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_moving_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;interpretive dance - either to the music or picking an object and embodying it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;try to fill up as much room as possible with your body&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;_sound_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;sound&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_sound_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;sit next to the practice rooms and listen to piano as you work&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;sing your poems, say them out loud - what do they sound like?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;_group_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;group&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_group_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;improv!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;many theater exercises that focus on &lt;del&gt;energy&lt;/del&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;counting up in a group&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;wah!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;group storytelling&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[draft] mythical spaces, or practicing magic as a topophil</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/places/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/places/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;unfinished first draft to be workshopped [VERY ROUGH :&amp;rsquo;)]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a mythical beast that few have seen. It is dreamy and beguiling and offers promises of dreams come true. Some have claimed to reap the benefits of its powers, others deny its existence. What is clear is that recently sightings have been low -  it seems to have disappeared, if it ever even existed. Many have hunted and still continue to hunt for this elusive creature in hopes of gaining its secrets: the fabled formula for work-life balance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>can&#39;t leave home without them</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/chopsticks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/chopsticks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;click slide clink slip push&lt;/em&gt; wooden chopsticks&lt;br&gt;&#xA;chasing charred duck drowning in soy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;click slide push slide slide&lt;/em&gt; the now flightless fowl&lt;br&gt;&#xA;nested on a bed of scallion evades my&lt;br&gt;&#xA;American grip with an uncomfortable liveliness&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;click squeeze slide push stab&lt;/em&gt; nothing like&lt;br&gt;&#xA;the the delicate caress of my parent’s movements&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;swish glide pinch rub stir&lt;/em&gt; their chopsticks&lt;br&gt;&#xA;a charming dance - I’m convinced they can do anything while&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I give up and stab an already dead bird&lt;br&gt;&#xA;the way I hold my chopsticks is the same way I hold my pencil&lt;br&gt;&#xA;two fingers over, two fingers under, stiff grip straight and tense&lt;br&gt;&#xA;my dad sees my hand - that is no way to write&lt;br&gt;&#xA;no way to use your chopsticks&lt;br&gt;&#xA;fist tight no room to relax, keep those letters round and neat like&lt;br&gt;&#xA;the textbooks where they teach me English and&lt;br&gt;&#xA;verb tenses that don’t exist in Chinese&lt;br&gt;&#xA;ate, eat, will eat&lt;br&gt;&#xA;吃， 吃， 吃&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I did learn something in elementary school&lt;br&gt;&#xA;eight years old, too young to understand what a culture is, what makes a culture unique&lt;br&gt;&#xA;yellow school bus to the only art museum in our forgotten southern town&lt;br&gt;&#xA;the only Chinese student on the bus&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>finding the right words</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/feb22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/feb22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;january 2022 - february 2022&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think about this quote (outside of any context) a lot&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Have you, dear reader, ever tried writing poetry that will set the collective soul of your nation on fire? If no, why not?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;3-1-22&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Lately it’s been hard to think - running from city to city and studio to classroom - I’m forgetting to feel the snow crunch beneath my feet and to take my mask off to smell the fresh air. I traveled to LA and spent a week in the woods near Yosemite before being whisked straight into my last undergraduate semester. The peace I found amongst the trees was hard to keep back in the city but the difference I found this time is most of what I am doing brings me great joy - I never thought I’d have to protect my time from myself, to make sure to take breaks from the activities I love to sit with myself and reflect. What has helped is disrupting my routine with reading, and surprisingly writing: something I said I would do for all of 2021 without forming a single sentence, a goal now manifested in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>good content: a list of lists</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/good-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/good-content/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;cool beans &amp;amp; other legumes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Books&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/9809.Invisible_Cities&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Invisible Cities&lt;/a&gt; by Italo Calvino&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Storyworthy-Engage-Persuade-through-Storytelling/dp/1608685489&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Storyworthy&lt;/a&gt; by Matthew Dicks (would recommend audiobook)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Art-Fear-Observations-Rewards-Artmaking/dp/0961454733&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Art &amp;amp; Fear: Observations On the Perils (and Rewards) of Artmaking&lt;/a&gt; by David Bayles, Ted Orland&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Opposite-Loneliness-Essays-Stories/dp/147675361X&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Opposite of Loneliness: Essays and Stories&lt;/a&gt; by Marina Keegan&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://design-justice.pubpub.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Design Justice&lt;/a&gt; by Sasha Costanza-Chock&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Cultish-Language-Fanaticism-Amanda-Montell/dp/0062993151&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cultish: The Language of Fanaticism&lt;/a&gt; by Amanda Montell&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Earth-Were-Briefly-Gorgeous-Novel/dp/0525562028&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;On Earth We&amp;rsquo;re Briefly Gorgeous&lt;/a&gt; by Ocean Vuong&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Metaphors-We-Live-George-Lakoff/dp/0226468011&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Metaphors We Live By&lt;/a&gt; [good skim] by George Lakoff, Mark Johnson&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/What-Artists-Do-Leonard-Koren/dp/0981484662&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;What Artists Do&lt;/a&gt; by Leonard Koren&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Hunger-Memoir-Body-Roxane-Gay/dp/0062362593&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hunger: A Memoir of (My) Body&lt;/a&gt; by Roxane Gay&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Crime-Punishment-Fyodor-Dostoyevsky/dp/0486415872&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Crime and Punishment&lt;/a&gt; by Fyodor Dostoyevsky&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/When-Breath-Becomes-Paul-Kalanithi/dp/081298840X&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;When Breath Becomes Air&lt;/a&gt; by Paul Kalanithi&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Wind-Up-Bird-Chronicle-Novel/dp/0679775439&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Wind-Up Bird Chronicle&lt;/a&gt; by Haruki Murakami&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Exhalation-Stories-Ted-Chiang/dp/1101947888&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Exhalation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Stories-Your-Life-Others-Chiang-ebook/dp/B0048EKOP0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Stories of Your Life and Others&lt;/a&gt; by Ted Chiang&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Axiomatic-Short-Stories-Science-Fiction/dp/1597805408&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Axiomatic&lt;/a&gt; by Greg Egan&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Remembrance-Earths-Past-Three-Body-Trilogy-ebook/dp/B01N198VU5&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Remembrance of Earth&amp;rsquo;s Past&lt;/a&gt; by Cixin Liu&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/All-Light-We-Cannot-See/dp/1501173219&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;All the Light We Cannot See&lt;/a&gt; by Anthony Doerr&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/This-How-You-Lose-Time/dp/1534430997&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This Is How You Lose the Time War&lt;/a&gt; by Amal El-Mohtar, Max Gladstone&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Poetry&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>fundamental questions</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quick questions jotted down as part of our cabin retreat planning activities. What are currently some fundamental questions in your life?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;how can art move a life?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what is the value of attention and observation? how can we be good witnesses?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what does it mean to create something?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;is there a way to increase serendipitous happenings?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what can we learn from others? what must we experience for ourselves?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what objects and ideas are our identities tethered to?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what does it mean to live together?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;how do words help or hinder us?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what other worlds can we build with conceptual metaphors?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;where does permission come from? to feel, express, and do&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what is the balance between observation and sharing?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;when does reflection become too much?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;are there any shoulds? what are they?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what makes a decision hard? what makes a decision good?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;where does technology grant us more agency?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what is creativity? where do computers fit in?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what does digital identity mean?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what is my relationship with technology? is technology necessary?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what stories/narratives have I rewritten about my past? what is the role of memory in identity?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what do I know to be true? what does it mean to be true to me?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what am I afraid of right now?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what do I like about being alone?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;why do I want more? what do I want more of&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what would my life be like if my actions aligned with what I say I value?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>on daily generation and planting seeds</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dailysketch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dailysketch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;a reflection on a month-ish of daily-ish sketches and the seeds that they nourished -&#xA;check them out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aliciaguo.com/daily-sketch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; 🤗&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/posts/site1.png&#34; alt=&#34;sketches on website&#34; style=&#34;width: 49%;&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/posts/site2.png&#34; alt=&#34;sketches on website&#34; style=&#34;width: 49%;&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/posts/site4.png&#34; alt=&#34;sketches on website&#34; style=&#34;width: 49%;&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/posts/site3.png&#34; alt=&#34;sketches on website&#34; style=&#34;width: 49%;&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On what it means to continue creating art&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;it means leaving some loose thread, some unresolved issue, to carry forward and explore in the next piece&amp;hellip;it means always carrying within you the seed crystal for your next destination.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-first-seed&#34;&gt;The First Seed &lt;a href=&#34;#the-first-seed&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometime around October, I participated with some friends in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/artsatmit/sets/72157720043991878/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;coding cypher&lt;/a&gt; as part of  a collaboration between MIT and Lupe Fiasco where we had the creative freedom to create pretty much anything artistic from a very vague prompt. &amp;ldquo;Cyphers flow freely between diverse performers who improvise their words, sounds, or movements to create a complex matrix of sharing,&amp;rdquo; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and our piece was an ambiguous improvised mixture of generative art, AI, and rapping. The paper-plate title lovingly and roastingly bestowed upon us was &amp;ldquo;most ambitious&amp;rdquo; (with ambitions not reached). I felt a little disappointed by my inability to realize my mind&amp;rsquo;s fantastical blueprints with code, believing that I would be able to generate the art I envisioned. I labeled myself as a generative artist, but created very little. The question I asked then and still am asking myself: what would my life be like if I acted like I cared about the things I said I did? As an exercise partially aimed at becoming better at manipulating creative code and partially just to prove to myself that I can keep up with an art habit, I challenged myself to do daily generative sketches.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>uncharted personal territory</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/other/uncharted/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/other/uncharted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to play more with these.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;private thought in public engagement&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;role of grief in society&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://subconscious.substack.com/p/possibility-space?s=r&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;possibility spaces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the transformative power of calligraphy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;perfecting a craft giving meaning to life&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;using apocalypses as fresh starts in speculative fiction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;why are glitches so cool&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;other forms of expressive text (telescopic, stretchy)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;music as heightened speech&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;rewriting narratives through public storytelling (see: the moth)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;how to see non-physical (digital?) desire paths &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>unedited words</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/other/poems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/other/poems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;some-words-arent-meant-to-be-edited-and-this-is-where-mine-live&#34;&gt;Some words aren&amp;rsquo;t meant to be edited, and this is where mine live. &lt;a href=&#34;#some-words-arent-meant-to-be-edited-and-this-is-where-mine-live&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;_permission-to-rage_&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;permission to rage&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_permission-to-rage_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;h6 id=&#34;_4-27-22_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;4-27-22&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_4-27-22_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was given permission today&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by a confession that slipped&lt;br&gt;&#xA;from under a tongue so still&lt;br&gt;&#xA;it had forgotten what it hid&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;until I sang with a choking sob&lt;br&gt;&#xA;words scratching my esophagus&lt;br&gt;&#xA;permission to rage&lt;br&gt;&#xA;granted by a truth let out&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;_bucket-list_&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;bucket list&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_bucket-list_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;h6 id=&#34;_4-6-22_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;4-6-22&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_4-6-22_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;p&gt;down sunny newbury street we’ll walk&lt;br&gt;&#xA;you’ll point at the people and I’ll watch you talk&lt;br&gt;&#xA;budding magnolias and cherry blossoms stretch in the warmth&lt;br&gt;&#xA;there’s a difference between pink buds, you’ll learn&lt;br&gt;&#xA;bricked path singing to the steps of our shoes&lt;br&gt;&#xA;a symphony of feet for a melody of two&lt;br&gt;&#xA;we must go see the flowers one last time&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;they’ll remain for the rest of the month,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;and a lifetime past mine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>what is art but a hope and a question?</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/art/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/art/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;a loose weaving of thoughts on (my) art and where I find myself in the creative ecosystem&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When asking myself why I create art, an incomplete but true answer would be because it’s what I’ve always done. In the moments that I am incapable of stringing together the right words, I turn to art. It’s how I find myself dealing with feelings - both those that I don’t want and those that I would like to preserve and hold close to take with me wherever I go. It’s a deeply personal act, whether or not that is my intention. I believe that is because it is impossible to hide from your creations, that everything ends up on display and it is entirely you, right now, in the present. What is reflected is who I am, not who I was or who I wish to be. She is the person with whom I engage and spend my time with. I can no more produce the same pieces as I did a year ago than I can create something that I’m not ready to make.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>what I know to be true [22]</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/other/whatiknow22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/other/whatiknow22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What I know to be true at 22, and possibly not at 23.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;What I know changes with each of the lives that I live.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;d be fun to do one of these every year :)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I know to be true is that attention and observation are what make life meaningful. &lt;strong&gt;I want to witness the world and the people in it.&lt;/strong&gt; Attending to myself, to friends, to nature, to strangers has never been more pressing. I have so many years left to spend with myself, and I’m excited to get to know her.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>entering a liminal space</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dec21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dec21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;december 2021 - january 2022&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;take note of the things that touch your heart, then you will know what you like&amp;rdquo; - Blue Period&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1-21-22&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I’m sitting on a plane to LA - in a liminal space within a larger liminal time. On the precipice of a new destination, but not quite there yet. Traveling. Questioning. The past two months were ones of reflection and searching for the things that touch my heart.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>when we are together</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/when-we-are-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/when-we-are-together/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;my dad&amp;rsquo;s hands gently coax shy dough balls he raised&lt;br&gt;&#xA;into imperfect circles they stretch&lt;br&gt;&#xA;glutinous strands&lt;br&gt;&#xA;reaching to hug&lt;br&gt;&#xA;the clockwise stir of my mom&amp;rsquo;s chopsticks&lt;br&gt;&#xA;teaching her filling to bond&lt;br&gt;&#xA;low-sodium over sister spices of scallion and ginger&lt;br&gt;&#xA;massaging oil into a fragmented mix&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I introduce wrapper and meat&lt;br&gt;&#xA;binding two ancestors with a tender fold and screaming pinch&lt;br&gt;&#xA;blood, not water, holds these dumplings&lt;br&gt;&#xA;completing their plump embrace&lt;br&gt;&#xA;lovenuggets nestled together upon a bed of cabbage&lt;br&gt;&#xA;family, we are&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characters With Character</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/characters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/characters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;column1&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;p&gt;Text can be as expressive as art, music, or a well placed line in a poem. Chinese characters have the potential to dance on the page - the individual strokes can flow and be combined in many ways. Characters With Character imbues an embodiment of action and state into Chinese characters themselves and explores expression through form.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;        &lt;ul&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt; 点 (diǎn): point / dot / drop / speck&#xA;        &lt;li&gt; 爆炸 (bào zhà): explosion / to explode&#xA;        &lt;li&gt; 扩大 (kuò dà): to expand / to enlarge&#xA;        &lt;li&gt; 融化 (róng huà): to melt / to thaw / to dissolve&#xA;        &lt;li&gt; 拥挤 (yōng jǐ): crowded / to throng / congestion&#xA;        &lt;li&gt; 故障 (gù zhàng): glitch/ malfunction&#xA;        &lt;li&gt; 墨水 (mò shuǐ): ink&#xA;        &lt;li&gt; 漩涡 (xuàn wō): swirl / vortex&#xA;        &lt;li&gt; 像素 (xiàng sù): pixel&#xA;        &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;column2 small-column border&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;a href=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/characters/dot.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/characters/dot.png&#34; alt=&#34;character of 点 made with dots&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;        &lt;a href=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/characters/explode.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/characters/explode.png&#34; alt=&#34;character of 爆炸 deconstructed&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;        &lt;a href=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/characters/expand.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/characters/expand.png&#34; alt=&#34;character of 扩大 enlarged in the center&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;        &lt;a href=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/characters/melt.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/characters/melt.png&#34; alt=&#34;character of 融化 squished in a melted manner&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;        &lt;a href=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/characters/crowd.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/characters/crowd.png&#34; alt=&#34;character of multiple copies of 拥挤&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;        &lt;a href=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/characters/glitch.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/characters/glitch.png&#34; alt=&#34;character of 故障 in a glitched image&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;        &lt;a href=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/characters/ink.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/characters/ink.png&#34; alt=&#34;character of 墨水 made with ink&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;        &lt;a href=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/characters/whirlpool.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/characters/whirlpool.png&#34; alt=&#34;character of 漩涡 with a swirl effect&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;        &lt;a href=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/characters/pixel.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/characters/pixel.png&#34; alt=&#34;character of pixelated 像素&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daily(ish) Sketches</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/wonder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/wonder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;column1&#34;&gt;&#xA;        View all sketches &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aliciaguo.com/daily-sketch/&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;mark&gt;here.&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;        See my &lt;a href=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/posts/dailysketch&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;mark&gt; blog post&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; about the process of making these daily sketches.&#xA;        &lt;p&gt;An exploration into the wonders of creative coding and randomness in algorithmic art. Each sketch is a short study into a concept, a formula, or technique. Made with P5js.&#xA;        &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;column2 small-column&#34;&gt;&#xA;        some favorites (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aliciaguo.com/daily-sketch/&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt;check out the rest!&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&#xA;        &lt;br&gt; butterfly lovers&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/wonder/1.gif&#34;  alt=&#34;two butterflies dancing&#34;/&gt;&#xA;        flow fields&#xA;        &lt;video class=&#34;tint&#34; muted=&#34;true&#34; loop autoplay playsinline style=&#34;width: 100%&#34;&gt;&#xA;                &lt;source&#xA;                  src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/wonder/1.mp4&#34;&#xA;                  type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&#xA;                /&gt;&#xA;              &lt;/video&gt;&#xA;        birth of a loofah&#xA;        &lt;video class=&#34;tint&#34; muted=&#34;true&#34; loop autoplay playsinline style=&#34;width: 100%&#34;&gt;&#xA;                &lt;source&#xA;                  src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/wonder/2.mp4&#34;&#xA;                  type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&#xA;                /&gt;&#xA;              &lt;/video&gt;&#xA;        parametric play&#xA;        &lt;video class=&#34;tint&#34; muted=&#34;true&#34; loop autoplay playsinline style=&#34;width: 100%&#34;&gt;&#xA;                &lt;source&#xA;                  src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/wonder/thmb.mp4&#34;&#xA;                  type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&#xA;                /&gt;&#xA;              &lt;/video&gt;&#xA;        procedural trees&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/wonder/2.gif&#34;  alt=&#34;procedural tree doing bicep curls&#34;/&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Growing Narratives</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/tree-rings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/tree-rings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;column1&#34;&gt;&#xA;        View Growing Narratives: Passage in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kernelmag.io/2/passage&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Kernel Issue 2.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;        &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Dendrochronology, also called tree-ring dating, [is] the scientific discipline concerned with dating and interpreting past events…” &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;        &lt;p&gt;Tree rings can tell us a lot about the passing of time, their shapes and thicknesses telling us stories of the past. They represent time, growth, and nourishment. Reading a cross section is, however, also an interpretation. The memories we carry can be written and rewritten depending on how we tell our stories  - in sustaining our rings, we grow our own narratives.&#xA;        &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;        &lt;i&gt;&lt;mark&gt;When we write and rewrite our narratives, when do memories become distorted?&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;        &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;        &lt;i&gt;Passage&lt;/i&gt; follows the thread of history as tree rings over time. They are malleable, affording the self a new vision of the past as lines thicken and intersect, weaving felt emotions and happenings into fresh narratives.&#xA;        &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;        &lt;i&gt;22&lt;/i&gt; represents the 22 full years I have lived. Each one has taught me something new about myself and nourished me in different areas. These are my growth rings. The thickness at each axis represents the nourishment and growth in individual years and I&#39;m happy to see that the rings are growing thicker with time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hell is Overthinking</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/hell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/hell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;column1&#34;&gt;&#xA;        View Hell is Overthinking in &lt;a href=&#34;https://taper.badquar.to/9/hell_is_overthinking.html&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Taper Issue #9&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;        &lt;p&gt;The 10th circle of hell must be that thought that won’t leave.&#xA;        &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;        Each refresh reveals a new intrusive, repetitive thought running in circles.&#xA;        &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;column2&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/comp_poetry/taper/hell.gif&#34;  alt=&#34;letters spinning in circles&#34;/&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life Plan</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/life_plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/life_plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;column1&#34;&gt;&#xA;        View Life Plan in &lt;a href=&#34;https://taper.badquar.to/9/life_plan.html&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Taper Issue #9&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;        &lt;p&gt;Folders are the perfect place to formulate a plan to accommodate all of&#xA;        the possibilities: how to proceed with a project, a future, a life.&#xA;        What other paths can be imagined? Choosing one folder enters you into a&#xA;        new realm, closed off to the other branches and revealing new&#xA;        directions.&#xA;        &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;        Can a life be planned out in your file explorer? &#xA;        &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;        Current work is on streamlining the creation process and including actual files.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>lolol</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/template/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/template/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;column1&#34;&gt;&#xA;        View TITLE in &lt;a href=&#34;link&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt;MAG&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;        &lt;p&gt;whee&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;column2&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;div class=&#34;exp-caption&#34;&gt;Passage&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/tree_rings/tree-rings.png&#34;  alt=&#34;artwork of generated tree rings arranged in a grid&#34;/&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oil Painting</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/intro_oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/intro_oil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;&#xA;I took an intro oil painting class and fell in love with the freedom of the material. The malleability is amazing.&#xA;    &lt;section class=&#34;gen-gallery&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/intro_oil/1.png&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/intro_oil/2.png&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/intro_oil/3.png&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/intro_oil/class1.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/intro_oil/class2.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/intro_oil/flower.png&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/intro_oil/ocean.png&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/intro_oil/rose1.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/intro_oil/rose2.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/intro_oil/rose3.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polanimation</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/polanimations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/polanimations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;column1&#34;&gt;&#xA;        Part of a research effort guided by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tichamelody.com/&#34;&gt;Ticha Sethapakdi&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;        &lt;p&gt;Polanimation explores how polarizers can be used as a passive display technology. The goal of Polanimation is to develop a design tool and fabrication process that allows users to create animated displays that take advantage of this effect. Can we design displays that are non-intrusive? Advertisements that can be filtered by viewers rather than the owners of the billboards?&#xA;        &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;        Polarizers are optical filters that allow only specific wavelengths of light to pass through. An interesting effect occurs when you place one polarizer in front of another: depending on the relative angles of the two polarizers, the opacity of the overlapping region changes. When the two polarizers are parallel to each other, the overlapping region will allow light to pass through and appear transparent. When they are perpendicular to each other, the overlapping region will block light and appear black. &#xA;        &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;        We can refer to the polarizer closest to the observer as the “viewing polarizer”. By placing multiple polarizers at different rotational offsets to the viewing polarizer and rotating the viewing polarizer, we can create various animation effects.   &#xA;        &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drawing for Designers</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/dfd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/dfd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;Sketches from MIT&#39;s Drawing for Designers studio class. Studies in movement, perspective, and lighting.&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This was the semester interruped by the pandemic, leading to imaginative sketches, blending the real and the remembered. &#xA;Many sketches were done from my room, adding elements of fantasy to transform the space into a space for speculation.&#xA;    &lt;section class=&#34;gen-gallery&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/1.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/10.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/1a.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/1b.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/1c.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/2.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/2a.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/2b.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/2c.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/3.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/3a.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/3b.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/3c.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/3d.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/4a.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/4b.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/4c.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/5c.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/6a.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/6b.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/6c.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/7.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/8.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/9.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/IMG_4966.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/IMG_4967.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/IMG_4974.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/IMG_4975.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/IMG_4978.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/IMG_5947-2.JPEG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/sketchbook/whee.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>100</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/design-100/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/design-100/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;column1&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;p&gt;Do something 100 times. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Then do it again. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And again.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;            100 rectangles x 3 iterations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;            Each new rectangle begins at the center of the previous, with the direction randomly chosen.&#xA;        &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;column2&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;video class=&#34;tint&#34; muted=&#34;true&#34; loop autoplay playsinline style=&#34;width: 100%&#34;&gt;&#xA;                &lt;source&#xA;                  src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/intro_design/time_lapse.mp4&#34;&#xA;                  type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&#xA;                /&gt;&#xA;              &lt;/video&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/intro_design/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;a bunch of rectangles in red and black&#34;/&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/intro_design/2.png&#34; alt=&#34;a bunch of rectangles in red and black&#34;/&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/intro_design/3.png&#34; alt=&#34;a bunch of rectangles in red and black&#34;/&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chalk of the Day</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/chalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/chalk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;&#xA;Daily chalk lettering in the Ray and Maria Stata Center.&#xA;&#xA;Check out our work on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/chalkoftheday/&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt;instagram.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;        &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;        Coverage by MIT News: &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.mit.edu/2020/drawing-daily-doodles-chalk-of-the-day-brightens-mit-0210&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Drawing daily doodles: Chalk of the Day brightens MIT&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;    &lt;section class=&#34;gen-gallery&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/8EA8291D-9294-4210-9DC8-05CB5077CD8B.JPG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/AEE7825C-A7FE-442C-90C4-8514F5D6BA16.JPG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/IMG_0026_Original.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/IMG_0112_Original.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/IMG_0130.JPG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/IMG_0254_Original.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/IMG_0296_Original.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/IMG_0370_Original.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/IMG_2583.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/IMG_2930%20Medium.png&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/IMG_2970.JPG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/IMG_3021.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/IMG_3112.JPG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/IMG_3311.JPG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/IMG_5815%20Medium.png&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/IMG_8224.JPG&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/IMG_8999_Original.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/Pineapple.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/Snapseed_Original%202.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/Snapseed_Original.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/chalk.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/explorations/chalk/thmb.png&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
