<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alicia Guo</title>
    <link>https://axguo.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alicia Guo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://axguo.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>things I do daily [live]</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/daily/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/daily/</guid>
      <description>These are the things I&amp;rsquo;ve committed to or keep coming back to. I wonder if these distract from bigger projects, after all, if I keep adding these small dailies my todos will eventually be filled but as for now I will keep these that bring me joy.
 morning pages: 3 page stream of consciousness journaling in the mornings painting a snippet of the sky: the gray weather depressed me so I decided to paint it every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2023: some world expanding moments</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/world-expanding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/world-expanding/</guid>
      <description>#single {font-family: &#34;Spectral&#34;, serif; font-weight: 300; font-size: 1.2em;} The phrase I keep coming back to this year is ✨ world-expanding. ✨ It applies to experiences, cities, people, and even the sky. When I see someone do that crazy something/live in a way that I didn’t even know was possible, it feels like my world has expanded: the possibility space for living has just grown that much bigger. This was written as a letter to a small group of friends but I wanted to share.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Turrell</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/turrell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/turrell/</guid>
      <description>It’s been over a week and I’m still thinking about James Turrell. The feeling of being in that room and seeing infinite space within the bounds that I know exist. The glow of the lights. The smoothness. The not knowing. The ethereal effect his pieces have with light sneaks into my thoughts in the form of questions. I remember standing in that room and wondering if my art could ever make someone feel like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT Showcase</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/mit-showcase/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/mit-showcase/</guid>
      <description> An interactive installation. Viewers could print out and take home the poems they made with Found Poem.    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes On Love</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/notes-on-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/notes-on-love/</guid>
      <description> A meditation on love. In collaboration with Harvard Conflux group.    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some things to be</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/to-be-something/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/to-be-something/</guid>
      <description>were not meant to be. I wish
to be lucky, enough
for the red I am wearing.
To be formless, genreless. Miscellaneous
always. To be willingly
categorized. I give you consent.
To be occasionally refreshing.
To be a factory of permissions.
To be a stronger vessel for my heart.
To be next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>reflections from a month(ish) of generative sketches</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/genuary23-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/genuary23-reflections/</guid>
      <description>Check out the sketches :)
Some thoughts on a month(ish) of generative sketches. I hesitate to use the word “generative” anymore because it’s been so overtaken by AI. What I mean here for my works are good old creative coding sketches, turtle graphics vibes and shaders. Pixels that have been handcrafted with care.   Pretty informal compared to my post last year and more of a collection of floating thoughts varying in importance to see if the challenge is worth doing again next year and in what capacity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Be a Poem</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/to-be-a-poem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/to-be-a-poem/</guid>
      <description> View the endless poem here. An exploration on things to be.
Inspired by Chen Chen&#39;s When I Grow Up I Want to Be a List of Further Possibilities. I love the use of &#34;to be&#34; as a yearning and exploration. Created with Rita.js and context-free grammars.
There&#39;s a bot and a poem too :)
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>steal like an artist</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/steal-like-an-artist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/steal-like-an-artist/</guid>
      <description>Steal like an artist is one of my favorite phrases to whisper to myself when I am sitting with indecision over a new project, to say that copying can lead to imitation which can lead to emulation and there is where new art is born. Stealing like an artist means being able to stitch together faint whiffs of past lives into new ones. It seems to me that there are two ways to begin at something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>uneven seasonings</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/uneven_seasoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/uneven_seasoning/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been cooking a lot recently and trying to find my way to being a capital C chef, the ones that are able to commune with their ingredients and just know which ones will be compatible and have that intuition for what proportions to include. I’m trying to find the secret sauce. The Food Lab by Kenji López-Alt sits on my shelf largely ignored for now due to my stubborn trial and error mindset wanting to develop this relationship naturally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>anyone can be a dancer</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/anyone_can_be_a_dancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/anyone_can_be_a_dancer/</guid>
      <description>A friend once told me that there must be something special about human faces that makes them so hard to draw — a certain elusive quality that comes from the ineffable experience of being human. This took me by surprise because I live with an extremely strong belief that it only takes practice, and relatively little at that, to obtain the skills necessary to draw a reasonable human face. It’s true that most attempts at facial features are awful, more resembling elongated emojis than facial features but I think that’s only because we take our faces for granted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I can do it, painfully</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/do-it-painfully/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/do-it-painfully/</guid>
      <description>Something wonderful has changed here. I feel so full of ideas, sending out pitches instead of finished work. Today I reached out to strangers (non-coders) asking if they wanted to collaborate on unspecified projects without knowing if I’d be able to help bring us to reach a shared vision. I felt giddy and sophisticated, like an artist about to graduate from faking it to making it.
A year ago I would have balked at the thought of offering to create something seemingly magical and impossible without a hint of a plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genuary 2023</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/genuary23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/genuary23/</guid>
      <description> View all sketches here.  blog post about the process of making these daily sketches. -- Reflection post coming soon. Daily creative sketches made using p5js following the prompts for January 2023. The focus for this month was learning and developing sketches to turn into larger art pieces later. You can play with them and re-generate your own unique sketch!  some favorites (check out the rest!) parametric blooms  more moiré  drunk thumbprint  wonderland colored contacts   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts from a dying mall</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dying-mall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dying-mall/</guid>
      <description>Wake up today feeling the vulnerability of winter. Fall leaves falling, leaving me exposed like every year before. Cold air rushing in the change of seasons and time running out, running towards an arbitrary new year, running towards made up deadlines. The ground becomes too stiff to bury old pictures, so I hang onto them in pockets that won’t fit more than half a person. I see my wishes being stripped naked like the orange trees that line the streets in a direction picked with a roll of the dice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I practice whispering</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/i-practice-whispering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/i-practice-whispering/</guid>
      <description>Crawling earthquakes are born of a thousand
whispered truths. Picking out crimson apricots,
bruising soft stones with my thumb.
Walking down stiff concrete streets
peeking around corners, wondering if a impish wind
has curved my words. If anyone can hear a daring
breath, humming lyrics never to be shared. I practice
singing in an empty parking lot—there is a dandelion
gathering his friends. I practice driving through
the same cracked road you first showed me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a wish from the heart’s left ventricle</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/wish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/wish/</guid>
      <description>back to the building from three years ago
sneaking in to the rhythm of the concierge’s nods.
I keep finding myself in places I know too well,
an overexposed photo of blurred bodies yet
my face sits clearly where it has always been
near new students that have learned to carry
their name tags in their mouths. the pink touch-me-nots
beg to be saved from the coming winter so I pluck</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>planting permission</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/planting-permission/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/planting-permission/</guid>
      <description>I love the mountains here because there are always dense collections of wildflowers under the tree line: purple buds sitting in crevices and yellow petals caressing their grassy neighbors. In places their beauty rivals the alps, the colorful fields an undeniable testimony to the power of nature undisturbed and to the charm of small wonders. They sway in the wind with a carefree attitude of the unbothered and unnamed, some immortalized and dried out by the sun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>what if writing was...</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/writing/</guid>
      <description>a map To begin with intentions is terribly important — by setting intentions for my writing, I see myself as marking the landscapes and the boundaries of the territory that I am embarking into. To set my intentions is to attempt to create the map of my mind as I know it now — undoubtedly incomplete and fated to be rearranged and re-rearranged, but it will be a starting point because no one begins with a blank map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cal Anderson</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/cal-anderson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/cal-anderson/</guid>
      <description>an irrational ratio
each hour spent at the park
parked outside the bookstore that
we never entered, spend an hour
on the phone, conveying a
secondhand kind of love to my
friend who hasn’t heard this
smile in my voice, it’s been so long
no body should ever be that warm
i might burn from the flutter of my legs
doing a silly dance, the audience gone
the performance is over but you are still here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut Feelings</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/gut-feelings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/gut-feelings/</guid>
      <description>If I trust my head. Twisted
vines creep to an unreachable
sun but knowledge sits in roots
tangled, knotted in biased hugs.
Amber words dissolve in a salty
river where flames steal my bark
and flesh. I swing between birds,
or are they stationary fish? See
my body lost in glass ferns,
too fragile to free.
If I trust my heart. Violent
spirits shake yellow chrysanthemums
growing from my chest. Soft painted</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>conversations in the dark</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/conversations-in-the-dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/conversations-in-the-dark/</guid>
      <description>Mi Pequeno San Juan by Nico Thomassin: I first saw this painting in a gallery in Puerto Rico and it forever will capture my feeling of awe to witness a whole city glow at night  I’m laughing and cradling my knees while the moon rises over a sun that has not yet said goodbye. It is an impossibly charming outlook of the entire city of Zürich from this rooftop that somehow is just taller than its neighbors but I still find myself looking forward to the ample clouds that pass by to cover the roundness of the moonlight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>things that are slow and sticky</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/slow-sticky/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/slow-sticky/</guid>
      <description>“Memory&amp;rsquo;s images, once they are fixed in words, are erased&amp;quot; - Italo Calvino, Invisible Cities
 I. 6 parts titanium white, 3 parts phthalo blue, 1 part ultramarine blue
a hint of napthol red and ochre yellow
a sky that bleeds saying goodbye
to a sun too quickly burning away
Walnuts can break a man, or at least they broke me. What other nut can be sold encased in an indestructible shell, cutting the hands of an eight year old determined to prove her strength?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Dine Alone</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dine/</guid>
      <description>You try to catch the waiter’s attention, but his focus skips over to the young couple by the window. They have just sat down, but there is twice the body to catch the eye — twice the hunger, twice the urgency. You give a small wave as he passes by, not enough for a friend, barely enough for the stranger. There is no need to be extravagant, no one is watching — movement from a still corner will always elicit surprise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>life&#39;s little gifts 🍃</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/lifesgifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/lifesgifts/</guid>
      <description>from life to me to you :)
 1-29-23  Unconference. Next time I will run a session/conversation.   1-28-23  Have you ever held an idea in your mind and tried to write it without words? I&amp;rsquo;m going further off the abstract deep end with asemic writing.   1-25-23  I NOW HAVE A VINTAGE CORONA FOUR TYPEWRITER. To feel the physicality of my typing like this is incredible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anatomy of the Collective</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/anatomy-of-the-collective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/anatomy-of-the-collective/</guid>
      <description>&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;
1: a branch of morphology that deals with the structure of organisms how to build a home
of identical red scaled roofs —
homeowner’s serpent
swallowing sounds
of mismatched bricks and cartoon walls covering
jelly beans spread on a child’s lap
how does she sort out the saccharine pebbles?
 sweet ribbon scarlet
of a blood that pumps in her heart but
my blood swirls gold and green with</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>explorations</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/explorations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/explorations/</guid>
      <description>noticing  touch things - the leaves on the bush or the wall of the old building and really feel the interaction take a walk down the street without earbuds and try to notice as many sounds as possible, there is a whole orchestra in traffic food meditations - appreciation for the flavors and textures before devouring live life as the main character in a Studio Ghibli movie - romanticize the little things and see the wind dance joyfully through the grass go on a walk - romanticize the little things, see myself as a studio ghibli movie people watch or listen - eavesdropping by a better name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[draft] mythical spaces, or practicing magic as a topophil</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/places/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/places/</guid>
      <description>unfinished first draft to be workshopped [VERY ROUGH :&#39;)]
There&amp;rsquo;s a mythical beast that few have seen. It is dreamy and beguiling and offers promises of dreams come true. Some have claimed to reap the benefits of its powers, others deny its existence. What is clear is that recently sightings have been low - it seems to have disappeared, if it ever even existed. Many have hunted and still continue to hunt for this elusive creature in hopes of gaining its secrets: the fabled formula for work-life balance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>can&#39;t leave home without them</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/chopsticks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/chopsticks/</guid>
      <description>click slide clink slip push wooden chopsticks
chasing charred duck drowning in soy
click slide push slide slide the now flightless fowl
nested on a bed of scallion evades my
American grip with an uncomfortable liveliness
click squeeze slide push stab nothing like
the the delicate caress of my parent’s movements
swish glide pinch rub stir their chopsticks
a charming dance - I’m convinced they can do anything while
I give up and stab an already dead bird</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>finding the right words</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/feb22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/feb22/</guid>
      <description>january 2022 - february 2022
I think about this quote (outside of any context) a lot1.
 “Have you, dear reader, ever tried writing poetry that will set the collective soul of your nation on fire? If no, why not?”
 3-1-22
Lately it’s been hard to think - running from city to city and studio to classroom - I’m forgetting to feel the snow crunch beneath my feet and to take my mask off to smell the fresh air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>good content: a list of lists</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/good-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/good-content/</guid>
      <description>cool beans &amp;amp; other legumes
Books
 Invisible Cities by Italo Calvino Storyworthy by Matthew Dicks (would recommend audiobook) Art &amp;amp; Fear: Observations On the Perils (and Rewards) of Artmaking by David Bayles, Ted Orland The Opposite of Loneliness: Essays and Stories by Marina Keegan Design Justice by Sasha Costanza-Chock Cultish: The Language of Fanaticism by Amanda Montell On Earth We&amp;rsquo;re Briefly Gorgeous by Ocean Vuong Metaphors We Live By [good skim] by George Lakoff, Mark Johnson What Artists Do by Leonard Koren Hunger: A Memoir of (My) Body by Roxane Gay Crime and Punishment by Fyodor Dostoyevsky When Breath Becomes Air by Paul Kalanithi The Wind-Up Bird Chronicle by Haruki Murakami Exhalation and Stories of Your Life and Others by Ted Chiang Axiomatic by Greg Egan Remembrance of Earth&amp;rsquo;s Past by Cixin Liu All the Light We Cannot See by Anthony Doerr This Is How You Lose the Time War by Amal El-Mohtar, Max Gladstone  Poetry</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fundamental questions</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/questions/</guid>
      <description>Quick questions jotted down as part of our cabin retreat planning activities. What are currently some fundamental questions in your life?
 how can art move a life? what is the value of attention and observation? how can we be good witnesses? what does it mean to create something? is there a way to increase serendipitous happenings? what can we learn from others? what must we experience for ourselves? what objects and ideas are our identities tethered to?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on daily generation and planting seeds</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dailysketch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dailysketch/</guid>
      <description>a reflection on a month-ish of daily-ish sketches and the seeds that they nourished - check them out here 🤗
    On what it means to continue creating art1:
 &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;it means leaving some loose thread, some unresolved issue, to carry forward and explore in the next piece&amp;hellip;it means always carrying within you the seed crystal for your next destination.&amp;rdquo;
  The First Seed Sometime around October, I participated with some friends in a coding cypher as part of a collaboration between MIT and Lupe Fiasco where we had the creative freedom to create pretty much anything artistic from a very vague prompt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>uncharted personal territory</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/other/uncharted/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/other/uncharted/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d like to play more with these.
  private thought in public engagement
  role of grief in society
  possibility spaces
  the transformative power of calligraphy
  perfecting a craft giving meaning to life
  using apocalypses as fresh starts in speculative fiction
  why are glitches so cool
  other forms of expressive text (telescopic, stretchy)
  music as heightened speech</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>unedited words</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/other/poems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/other/poems/</guid>
      <description>Some words aren&amp;rsquo;t meant to be edited, and this is where mine live.  permission to rage 4-27-22 I was given permission today
by a confession that slipped
from under a tongue so still
it had forgotten what it hid
until I sang with a choking sob
words scratching my esophagus
permission to rage
granted by a truth let out
bucket list 4-6-22 down sunny newbury street we’ll walk
you’ll point at the people and I’ll watch you talk</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>what is art but a hope and a question?</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/art/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/art/</guid>
      <description>a loose weaving of thoughts on (my) art and where I find myself in the creative ecosystem
When asking myself why I create art, an incomplete but true answer would be because it’s what I’ve always done. In the moments that I am incapable of stringing together the right words, I turn to art. It’s how I find myself dealing with feelings - both those that I don’t want and those that I would like to preserve and hold close to take with me wherever I go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>what I know to be true [22]</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/other/whatiknow22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/other/whatiknow22/</guid>
      <description>What I know to be true at 22, and possibly not at 23.
What I know changes with each of the lives that I live.
I think it&amp;rsquo;d be fun to do one of these every year :)
  What I know to be true is that attention and observation are what make life meaningful. I want to witness the world and the people in it. Attending to myself, to friends, to nature, to strangers has never been more pressing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>entering a liminal space</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dec21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dec21/</guid>
      <description>december 2021 - january 2022
 &amp;ldquo;take note of the things that touch your heart, then you will know what you like&amp;rdquo; - Blue Period
 1-21-22
I’m sitting on a plane to LA - in a liminal space within a larger liminal time. On the precipice of a new destination, but not quite there yet. Traveling. Questioning. The past two months were ones of reflection and searching for the things that touch my heart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>when we are together</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/when-we-are-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/when-we-are-together/</guid>
      <description>my dad&amp;rsquo;s hands gently coax shy dough balls he raised
into imperfect circles they stretch
glutinous strands
reaching to hug
the clockwise stir of my mom&amp;rsquo;s chopsticks
teaching her filling to bond
low-sodium over sister spices of scallion and ginger
massaging oil into a fragmented mix
I introduce wrapper and meat
binding two ancestors with a tender fold and screaming pinch
blood, not water, holds these dumplings
completing their plump embrace</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characters With Character</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/characters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/characters/</guid>
      <description> Text can be as expressive as art, music, or a well placed line in a poem. Chinese characters have the potential to dance on the page - the individual strokes can flow and be combined in many ways. Characters With Character imbues an embodiment of action and state into Chinese characters themselves and explores expression through form.
  点 (diǎn): point / dot / drop / speck  爆炸 (bào zhà): explosion / to explode  扩大 (kuò dà): to expand / to enlarge  融化 (róng huà): to melt / to thaw / to dissolve  拥挤 (yōng jǐ): crowded / to throng / congestion  故障 (gù zhàng): glitch/ malfunction  墨水 (mò shuǐ): ink  漩涡 (xuàn wō): swirl / vortex  像素 (xiàng sù): pixel              </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily(ish) Sketches</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/wonder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/wonder/</guid>
      <description> View all sketches here. See my  blog post about the process of making these daily sketches. An exploration into the wonders of creative coding and randomness in algorithmic art. Each sketch is a short study into a concept, a formula, or technique. Made with P5js.  some favorites (check out the rest!) butterfly lovers flow fields  birth of a loofah  parametric play  procedural trees   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing Narratives</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/tree-rings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/tree-rings/</guid>
      <description>View Growing Narratives: Passage in Kernel Issue 2. “Dendrochronology, also called tree-ring dating, [is] the scientific discipline concerned with dating and interpreting past events…” 1
Tree rings can tell us a lot about the passing of time, their shapes and thicknesses telling us stories of the past. They represent time, growth, and nourishment. Reading a cross section is, however, also an interpretation. The memories we carry can be written and rewritten depending on how we tell our stories - in sustaining our rings, we grow our own narratives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hell is Overthinking</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/hell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/hell/</guid>
      <description> View Hell is Overthinking in Taper Issue #9 The 10th circle of hell must be that thought that won’t leave. Each refresh reveals a new intrusive, repetitive thought running in circles.    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Plan</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/life_plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/life_plan/</guid>
      <description>View Life Plan in Taper Issue #9 Folders are the perfect place to formulate a plan to accommodate all of the possibilities: how to proceed with a project, a future, a life. What other paths can be imagined? Choosing one folder enters you into a new realm, closed off to the other branches and revealing new directions. Can a life be planned out in your file explorer? Current work is on streamlining the creation process and including actual files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lolol</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/template/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/template/</guid>
      <description> View TITLE in MAG whee
 Passage   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oil Painting</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/intro_oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/intro_oil/</guid>
      <description> I took an intro oil painting class and fell in love with the freedom of the material. The malleability is amazing.    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polanimation</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/polanimations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/polanimations/</guid>
      <description>Part of a research effort guided by Ticha Sethapakdi Polanimation explores how polarizers can be used as a passive display technology. The goal of Polanimation is to develop a design tool and fabrication process that allows users to create animated displays that take advantage of this effect. Can we design displays that are non-intrusive? Advertisements that can be filtered by viewers rather than the owners of the billboards? Polarizers are optical filters that allow only specific wavelengths of light to pass through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drawing for Designers</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/dfd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/dfd/</guid>
      <description> Sketches from MIT&#39;s Drawing for Designers studio class. Studies in movement, perspective, and lighting. This was the semester interruped by the pandemic, leading to imaginative sketches, blending the real and the remembered. Many sketches were done from my room, adding elements of fantasy to transform the space into a space for speculation.    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/design-100/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/design-100/</guid>
      <description> Do something 100 times. Then do it again. And again.
100 rectangles x 3 iterations.
Each new rectangle begins at the center of the previous, with the direction randomly chosen.     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chalk of the Day</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/chalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/chalk/</guid>
      <description> Daily chalk lettering in the Ray and Maria Stata Center. Check out our work on instagram. Coverage by MIT News: Drawing daily doodles: Chalk of the Day brightens MIT    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
