<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>living on Alicia Guo</title>
    <link>https://axguo.github.io/tags/living/</link>
    <description>Recent content in living on Alicia Guo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://axguo.github.io/tags/living/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>explorations</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/explorations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/explorations/</guid>
      <description>noticing  touch things - the leaves on the bush or the wall of the old building and really feel the interaction take a walk down the street without earbuds and try to notice as many sounds as possible, there is a whole orchestra in traffic food meditations - appreciation for the flavors and textures before devouring live life as the main character in a Studio Ghibli movie - romanticize the little things and see the wind dance joyfully through the grass go on a walk - romanticize the little things, see myself as a studio ghibli movie people watch or listen - eavesdropping by a better name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fundamental questions</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/questions/</guid>
      <description>Quick questions jotted down as part of our cabin retreat planning activities. What are currently some fundamental questions in your life?
 how can art move a life? what is the value of attention and observation? how can we be good witnesses? what does it mean to create something? is there a way to increase serendipitous happenings? what can we learn from others? what must we experience for ourselves? what objects and ideas are our identities tethered to?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
