<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Living on Alicia Guo</title>
    <link>https://axguo.github.io/tags/living/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Living on Alicia Guo</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://axguo.github.io/tags/living/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>uneven seasonings</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/uneven_seasoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/uneven_seasoning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been cooking a lot recently and trying to find my way to being a capital C chef, the ones that are able to commune with their ingredients and just know which ones will be compatible and have that intuition for what proportions to include. I’m trying to find the secret sauce. The Food Lab by Kenji López-Alt sits on my shelf largely ignored for now due to my stubborn trial and error mindset wanting to develop this relationship naturally. In short, I’m reinventing the wheel. Maybe most of the reason I haven’t gotten around to the book is it is big and intimidating and I was lazy. But I love watching Food Wars while I cook — it’s an entire anime dedicated to discovering food through exploration, trying and failing and stuffed with so many mouth watering animations that make me sad knowing that real food will never look as appetizing. I’m motivated and inspired to be adventurous with my recipes. I want to make them mine, to cross over into the realm of food as art. The episodes are also full of food science and molecular gastronomy to varying degrees of exaggeration and accuracy where my fact check consists not of google but just just trying the thing. One of the plot-twisting moments comes from using uneven flavors — spreading seasoning in varying areas and concentrations over a smooth uniform distribution — to enhance taste. Each bite becomes a surprise, a shifting dance of unexpected flavors and avoids becoming one dimensional. I haven’t tested this fully - it certainly is true for sauces: drizzling and dipping often taste better than dousing a food in sauce. This also checks out with most of the recipes I’ve read and watched. Salt/oil/seasonings are sprinkled on haphazardly and for many years I wondered why they weren’t mixed or massaged better as to be more uniform. Whenever I would, I’d discover that it clearly did not taste as good.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>explorations</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/explorations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/explorations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;_noticing_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;noticing&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_noticing_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;touch things - the leaves on the bush or the wall of the old building and really feel the interaction&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;take a walk down the street without earbuds and try to notice as many sounds as possible, there is a whole orchestra in traffic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;food meditations - appreciation for the flavors and textures before devouring&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;live life as the main character in a Studio Ghibli movie - romanticize the little things and see the wind dance joyfully through the grass&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;go on a walk - romanticize the little things, see myself as a studio ghibli movie&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;people watch or listen - eavesdropping by a better name. come up with wild stories for each human or object&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;how high is the ceiling right now?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;_living-poetically_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;living poetically&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_living-poetically_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;carry a notebook around and write/doodle all of life’s gifts&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;journal at a park&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I like parks&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;live at parks, bring a blanket and a good book&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;art museums as nourishment of the soul, not mind - focus on the feelings&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;turning spaces into new places&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;sitting at night and feeling the infinite expanse of not being able to see boundaries&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;transform spaces with music and scents&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;_art_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;art&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_art_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;gesture drawings - 30 second sketches to capture the _essence _of a person&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;blind contour drawings - don’t look at the page and release yourself from the shackles of perfection and give yourself permission to notice details&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;make rubbings of objects. touch them. feel them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;zoooooom in&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;self portraits, but make them short and interpretive&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;_writing_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;writing&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_writing_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what did you eat today? write a poem in 10 minutes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what sounds do the objects in your life make? find their rhythms - what do they sound like?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;_moving_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;moving&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_moving_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;interpretive dance - either to the music or picking an object and embodying it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;try to fill up as much room as possible with your body&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;_sound_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;sound&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_sound_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;sit next to the practice rooms and listen to piano as you work&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;sing your poems, say them out loud - what do they sound like?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;_group_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;group&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_group_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;improv!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;many theater exercises that focus on &lt;del&gt;energy&lt;/del&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;counting up in a group&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;wah!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;group storytelling&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>fundamental questions</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quick questions jotted down as part of our cabin retreat planning activities. What are currently some fundamental questions in your life?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;how can art move a life?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what is the value of attention and observation? how can we be good witnesses?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what does it mean to create something?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;is there a way to increase serendipitous happenings?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what can we learn from others? what must we experience for ourselves?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what objects and ideas are our identities tethered to?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what does it mean to live together?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;how do words help or hinder us?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what other worlds can we build with conceptual metaphors?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;where does permission come from? to feel, express, and do&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what is the balance between observation and sharing?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;when does reflection become too much?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;are there any shoulds? what are they?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what makes a decision hard? what makes a decision good?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;where does technology grant us more agency?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what is creativity? where do computers fit in?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what does digital identity mean?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what is my relationship with technology? is technology necessary?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what stories/narratives have I rewritten about my past? what is the role of memory in identity?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what do I know to be true? what does it mean to be true to me?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what am I afraid of right now?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what do I like about being alone?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;why do I want more? what do I want more of&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what would my life be like if my actions aligned with what I say I value?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
