<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>generative art on Alicia Guo</title>
    <link>https://axguo.github.io/tags/generative-art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in generative art on Alicia Guo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://axguo.github.io/tags/generative-art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>reflections from a month(ish) of generative sketches</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/genuary23-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/genuary23-reflections/</guid>
      <description>Check out the sketches :)
Some thoughts on a month(ish) of generative sketches. I hesitate to use the word “generative” anymore because it’s been so overtaken by AI. What I mean here for my works are good old creative coding sketches, turtle graphics vibes and shaders. Pixels that have been handcrafted with care.   Pretty informal compared to my post last year and more of a collection of floating thoughts varying in importance to see if the challenge is worth doing again next year and in what capacity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on daily generation and planting seeds</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dailysketch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dailysketch/</guid>
      <description>a reflection on a month-ish of daily-ish sketches and the seeds that they nourished - check them out here 🤗
    On what it means to continue creating art1:
 &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;it means leaving some loose thread, some unresolved issue, to carry forward and explore in the next piece&amp;hellip;it means always carrying within you the seed crystal for your next destination.&amp;rdquo;
  The First Seed Sometime around October, I participated with some friends in a coding cypher as part of a collaboration between MIT and Lupe Fiasco where we had the creative freedom to create pretty much anything artistic from a very vague prompt.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
