<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>art on Alicia Guo</title>
    <link>https://axguo.github.io/tags/art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in art on Alicia Guo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://axguo.github.io/tags/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>reflections from a month(ish) of generative sketches</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/genuary23-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/genuary23-reflections/</guid>
      <description>Check out the sketches :)
Some thoughts on a month(ish) of generative sketches. I hesitate to use the word “generative” anymore because it’s been so overtaken by AI. What I mean here for my works are good old creative coding sketches, turtle graphics vibes and shaders. Pixels that have been handcrafted with care.   Pretty informal compared to my post last year and more of a collection of floating thoughts varying in importance to see if the challenge is worth doing again next year and in what capacity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>steal like an artist</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/steal-like-an-artist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/steal-like-an-artist/</guid>
      <description>Steal like an artist is one of my favorite phrases to whisper to myself when I am sitting with indecision over a new project, to say that copying can lead to imitation which can lead to emulation and there is where new art is born. Stealing like an artist means being able to stitch together faint whiffs of past lives into new ones. It seems to me that there are two ways to begin at something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on daily generation and planting seeds</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dailysketch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dailysketch/</guid>
      <description>a reflection on a month-ish of daily-ish sketches and the seeds that they nourished - check them out here 🤗
    On what it means to continue creating art1:
 &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;it means leaving some loose thread, some unresolved issue, to carry forward and explore in the next piece&amp;hellip;it means always carrying within you the seed crystal for your next destination.&amp;rdquo;
  The First Seed Sometime around October, I participated with some friends in a coding cypher as part of a collaboration between MIT and Lupe Fiasco where we had the creative freedom to create pretty much anything artistic from a very vague prompt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>what is art but a hope and a question?</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/art/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/art/</guid>
      <description>a loose weaving of thoughts on (my) art and where I find myself in the creative ecosystem
When asking myself why I create art, an incomplete but true answer would be because it’s what I’ve always done. In the moments that I am incapable of stringing together the right words, I turn to art. It’s how I find myself dealing with feelings - both those that I don’t want and those that I would like to preserve and hold close to take with me wherever I go.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
