<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on Alicia Guo</title>
    <link>https://axguo.github.io/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on Alicia Guo</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://axguo.github.io/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>planting permission</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/planting-permission/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/planting-permission/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/posts/swiss_mountain.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;view of the swiss mountains&#34; style=&#34;width: 60%;&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I love the mountains here because there are always dense collections of wildflowers under the tree line: purple buds sitting in crevices and yellow petals caressing their grassy neighbors. In places their beauty rivals the alps, the colorful fields an undeniable testimony to the power of nature undisturbed and to the charm of small wonders. They sway in the wind with a carefree attitude of the unbothered and unnamed, some immortalized and dried out by the sun. A few are now resting pressed in my notebook. I try to search for their names. I can’t find any—in another life, one not so forgiving, they would have been known as weeds. White puffballs are the most abundant amongst these mountainside stems, holding globes of dandelion seeds resting half undressed. Dandelions were once celebrated in magic and medicine. Now they’re relentlessly eradicated from lawns and city grass.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>conversations in the dark</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/conversations-in-the-dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/conversations-in-the-dark/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://axguo.github.io/images/posts/nico.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;painting of a colorful city of lights on a hill at night&#34; style=&#34;width: 49%;&#34;/&gt; &#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;img-caption&#34; style=&#34;width: 49%;&#34;&gt;Mi Pequeno San Juan by Nico Thomassin: I first saw this painting in a gallery in Puerto Rico and it forever will capture my feeling of awe to witness a whole city glow at night&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m laughing and cradling my knees while the moon rises over a sun that has not yet said goodbye. It is an impossibly charming outlook of the entire city of Zürich from this rooftop that somehow is just taller than its neighbors but I still find myself looking forward to the ample clouds that pass by to cover the roundness of the moonlight. Because in the dark, I stop caring about most things. I can feel my face relax, free to move into configurations that no one will see, unburdened by the weight of a smile that always lasts too long. My body reacts in ways unchecked with loose chuckles and shifts of surprise. No one can see me, or so I’d like to believe. What exists in the dark is only the floating voices and a heightened perception of how I feel, and in this moment I am happy. Happy to feel so comfortable sitting around cold pizza with new friends on top of a whole city and happy that silent pauses feel less heavy in the dark. I could close my eyes and hear the exclamations around me and pick out each unique laugh. The absence of light is a blessing for someone who sometimes overthinks, attuned to the minuscule shifts in another’s demeanor. It’s no wonder that some of my favorite conversations have happened at night: lying on the pier under the stars and spilling out our heartaches, jokes on a dark park bench, or conversations like this, where daylight faded and we decided to stay. I think it’s the same reason why I prefer phone calls to video chat: when everything else is stripped away except voice, we fill up the space in a raw, unfiltered way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
