<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>travel on Alicia Guo</title>
    <link>https://axguo.github.io/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in travel on Alicia Guo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://axguo.github.io/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>planting permission</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/planting-permission/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/planting-permission/</guid>
      <description>I love the mountains here because there are always dense collections of wildflowers under the tree line: purple buds sitting in crevices and yellow petals caressing their grassy neighbors. In places their beauty rivals the alps, the colorful fields an undeniable testimony to the power of nature undisturbed and to the charm of small wonders. They sway in the wind with a carefree attitude of the unbothered and unnamed, some immortalized and dried out by the sun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>conversations in the dark</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/conversations-in-the-dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/conversations-in-the-dark/</guid>
      <description>Mi Pequeno San Juan by Nico Thomassin: I first saw this painting in a gallery in Puerto Rico and it forever will capture my feeling of awe to witness a whole city glow at night  I’m laughing and cradling my knees while the moon rises over a sun that has not yet said goodbye. It is an impossibly charming outlook of the entire city of Zürich from this rooftop that somehow is just taller than its neighbors but I still find myself looking forward to the ample clouds that pass by to cover the roundness of the moonlight.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
