<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Note on Alicia Guo</title>
    <link>https://axguo.github.io/categories/note/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Note on Alicia Guo</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://axguo.github.io/categories/note/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>things I do daily [live]</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/daily/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/daily/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are the things I&amp;rsquo;ve committed to or keep coming back to. I wonder if these distract from bigger projects, after all, if I keep adding these small dailies my todos will eventually be filled but as for now I will keep these that bring me joy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aliciaguo.com/morning-pages/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;morning pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: 3 page stream of consciousness journaling in the mornings&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/patchwork.letters/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;painting a snippet of the sky&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: the gray weather depressed me so I decided to paint it every day. now I notice so much in the sky that I&amp;rsquo;m endlessly fascinated regardless of the weather.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vShqauv5ofA0p5P-v_X-UnV4MlW9fudWjCu-VLTyNuV4dNIsScjZ6zB4HOLahLTtQ_WRRjUWNwwVkzn/pubhtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a poem a day keeps the blues at bay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: it&amp;rsquo;s surprising how much five minutes a day can ground me.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20 min dance session at night&lt;/strong&gt;: I wiggle and wave like a crazy person before I sleep. this is a pillar of my happiness.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;seasonal&#34;&gt;seasonal &lt;a href=&#34;#seasonal&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hyperlink.academy/s/mangotango/s/77pAGMrlZ2JMZgde4Zr6Ov/paper%20%26%20thread&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;paper &amp;amp; thread [march 2024]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: daily handmade projects on Hyperlink Academy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>James Turrell</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/turrell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/turrell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been over a week and I’m still thinking about James Turrell. The feeling of being in that room and seeing infinite space within the bounds that I know exist. The glow of the lights. The smoothness. The not knowing. The ethereal effect his pieces have with light sneaks into my thoughts in the form of questions. I remember standing in that room and wondering if my art could ever make someone feel like this. What materials can I use? What technologies are still mysterious enough to elicit wonder through not knowing how they work? What was most fun was trying to reverse engineer his effects with friends. What direction can I explore deeply enough in? What group of people can I find? Turrell had a group to experiment with. I love that with Turrell’s works I feel like I could sit there for hours &amp;ndash; it’s a feeling I actively seek to foster in my web-based pieces, and something I only just now realized I could aim for in real life too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>steal like an artist</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/steal-like-an-artist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/steal-like-an-artist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steal like an artist&lt;/em&gt; is one of my favorite phrases to whisper to myself when I am sitting with indecision over a new project, to say that copying can lead to imitation which can lead to emulation and there is where new art is born. Stealing like an artist means being able to stitch together faint whiffs of past lives into new ones. It seems to me that there are two ways to begin at something. Either being a direct student (ex: following tutorials) or copying (attempting to recreate). The best curriculum is a combination of both and I’m thankful for my first creative coding class taught by Zach Lieberman (amazing artist and prof!) called Recreating the Past. Our whole class was focused on examining artists’ past works and selecting a few to code up while giving us the general tools to do so. These art pieces we tried to recreate consisted not just of digital artifacts, but animations, interactive installations, sketches, and textiles. It was a blessing to be given the permission to forget trying to be original in content and focus on the process. The destination was given and we were tasked with mapping out the journey and oddly enough there was a feeling of something resembling originality in this piecing together of existing work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>uneven seasonings</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/uneven_seasoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/uneven_seasoning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been cooking a lot recently and trying to find my way to being a capital C chef, the ones that are able to commune with their ingredients and just know which ones will be compatible and have that intuition for what proportions to include. I’m trying to find the secret sauce. The Food Lab by Kenji López-Alt sits on my shelf largely ignored for now due to my stubborn trial and error mindset wanting to develop this relationship naturally. In short, I’m reinventing the wheel. Maybe most of the reason I haven’t gotten around to the book is it is big and intimidating and I was lazy. But I love watching Food Wars while I cook — it’s an entire anime dedicated to discovering food through exploration, trying and failing and stuffed with so many mouth watering animations that make me sad knowing that real food will never look as appetizing. I’m motivated and inspired to be adventurous with my recipes. I want to make them mine, to cross over into the realm of food as art. The episodes are also full of food science and molecular gastronomy to varying degrees of exaggeration and accuracy where my fact check consists not of google but just just trying the thing. One of the plot-twisting moments comes from using uneven flavors — spreading seasoning in varying areas and concentrations over a smooth uniform distribution — to enhance taste. Each bite becomes a surprise, a shifting dance of unexpected flavors and avoids becoming one dimensional. I haven’t tested this fully - it certainly is true for sauces: drizzling and dipping often taste better than dousing a food in sauce. This also checks out with most of the recipes I’ve read and watched. Salt/oil/seasonings are sprinkled on haphazardly and for many years I wondered why they weren’t mixed or massaged better as to be more uniform. Whenever I would, I’d discover that it clearly did not taste as good.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>anyone can be a dancer</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/anyone_can_be_a_dancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/anyone_can_be_a_dancer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A friend once told me that there must be something special about human faces that makes them so hard to draw — a certain elusive quality that comes from the ineffable experience of being human. This took me by surprise because I live with an extremely strong belief that it only takes practice, and relatively little at that, to obtain the skills necessary to draw a reasonable human face. It’s true that most attempts at facial features are awful, more resembling elongated emojis than facial features but I think that’s only because we take our faces for granted. How often do we really notice individual shapes that make up our face, the new freckles from the sun or the path of wrinkles that surface from a smile? Can you conjure up the contours of your friend’s face the same way you can a rolling chair or a head of broccoli? It’s impossible to draw what you can’t see. One of my favorite classes in undergrad was a studio drawing class, and within the first two classes totalling six hours students went from alien scribbles to stunningly accurate sketches. It was one of the most formative “you can do anything with enough practice” lessons I witnessed. The difference was that they weren’t engaging in brute forcing their practice. Our prof consistently stressed attention to detail and often would ask us to verbalize our observations when things seemed off, making them easier to translate to paper. The results were by no means close to photographic, but in a way they were better. There was a raw charm to the character imbued by the individual artists who had learned to direct their observations but had not yet succumbed to paralyzing intense scrutinizing of their own work. So, yes, I believe that anyone can learn to draw a face within a day with the right instruction. Today I told a dancer that I’m not great at dancing (though I do enjoy it) and she responded with the good old “anyone can learn to dance with enough practice!” And it hit me that she probably sees dance the same way I see art. The trick to leveling up fast in drawing is to learn how to observe. I wonder what is for dance (I’m going to ask next time I see her) and what it is for all of the other areas of study, the ones that can be practiced. I&amp;rsquo;m grateful that I can understand this deeply through art. I imagine it takes a bit more time for a subject such as physics or glassblowing. The seed to be an artist is something that everyone has been doing to different degrees their entire lives! We observe so many details every single day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I can do it, painfully</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/do-it-painfully/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/do-it-painfully/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Something wonderful has changed here. I feel so full of ideas, sending out pitches instead of finished work. Today I reached out to strangers (non-coders) asking if they wanted to collaborate on unspecified projects without knowing if I’d be able to help bring us to reach a shared vision. I felt giddy and sophisticated, like an artist about to graduate from faking it to making it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A year ago I would have balked at the thought of offering to create something seemingly magical and impossible without a hint of a plan. I had just as many ideas, less formed, more wobbly and ungrounded, floating within the realm of &lt;a href=&#34;https://autotranslucence.wordpress.com/2018/03/30/becoming-a-magician/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;magicians&lt;/a&gt;. A pitch was a proposal and a promise. A promise to deliver if chosen and I didn’t think I could. I’ve learned a few things since then, have since learned to have confidence in myself that &lt;em&gt;I can figure it out, though maybe with a lot of pain.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>life&#39;s little gifts 🍃</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/lifesgifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/lifesgifts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;from life to me to you :)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-29-23&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Unconference. Next time I will run a session/conversation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-28-23&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Have you ever held an idea in your mind and tried to write it without words? I&amp;rsquo;m going further off the abstract deep end with asemic writing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-25-23&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I NOW HAVE A VINTAGE CORONA FOUR TYPEWRITER. To feel the physicality of my typing like this is incredible.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-21-23&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grateful to be spending the first Chinese New Year at home in four years. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to be a little superstitious this year since it&amp;rsquo;s the year of the rabbit and wear red for luck. I find these traditions more and more inevitable.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;12-27-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When it&amp;rsquo;s cold in Texas all of the shrubs get blankets.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;12-25-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Being released from quarantine for the holidays is a blessing. I am so grateful for the mundane. Of being able to eat meals with my parents and coexist in the same spaces.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;4-19-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Orchid mantis! A mantis that looks like an orchid! They exist!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;4-7-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You can be a greedy reader. I’m a greedy writer.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3-19-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Feeling comfortable within a group is a gift. I feel so comfortable in my body and emotions right now.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3-13-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Erie Meyer describing how special Lina Khan is - “she’s a jelly bean!” 🥺&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3-12-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Housewarmings! Warm house. House friends. New friends. I feel warm.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3-9-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Painting through the night alone in the studio is an S tier experience. I spent three hours painting fabric with snow falling at the window and have never felt more relaxed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3-3-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I love love love small classes that turn into family. I feel so comfortable in my writing class workshopping or even just sitting and sharing hot takes. How can we support more small-scale communities like this?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-25-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;​​The spaces I occupy constantly shift into new places. Spending hours meditating on the ground with raindrop music transforms my room into a soft, glowing forest. What other spaces can I change into places?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-21-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;​​“Murder your darlings” -Sir Arthur Quiller-Couch. What a great way of phrasing advice on how to not get stuck artistically. Time to kill my darlings and move on to new creative happenings.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-19-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Started reading Mythos by Stephen Fry and I&amp;rsquo;m already very excited. The Greeks believed that began not with a god or a bang, but CHAOS.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-15-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thinking of writing not as work (which breeds reluctance) nor relaxation (a fickle association), but as &lt;em&gt;endurance&lt;/em&gt;. In the same way that running is painful and you want to die until it&amp;rsquo;s not and becomes enjoyable (at least for me), writing&amp;rsquo;s benefits are felt over time and can be difficult in the day to day.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-14-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Telescopic text!! This guy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/_jzhao/status/1493274555921674255?s=20&amp;amp;t=zpUqbdXsUVogVfFKU9-PZg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;gift&lt;/a&gt; to his girlfriend is also a gift to me because I&amp;rsquo;m now PUMPED to try this new art form. Can&amp;rsquo;t wait to write some telescopic poems. This is what gets me excited about creative tools and open source.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-10-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sculpting, oil painting, frosting - there&amp;rsquo;s not much difference. Working with a thick malleable medium with a knife. It&amp;rsquo;s too easy to imagine that the paint flowers I am spreading are made of a yummy buttercream frosting.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-6-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spent a day crash coursing myself on differential equations and signal processing for a class I want to take. Fun moments like these remind me of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sive.rs/kimo#:~:text=If%20you%27re%20more%20driven,ve%20had%20no%20speed%20limit.&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;no speed limit article&lt;/a&gt; by Sivers and I should really do this more often.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-5-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Attended the symphony with my roommates and listened to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://handelandhaydn.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bach Brandenburg Concertos&lt;/a&gt;. This was my first time witnessing such an intimate concert: cozy theater, small group of musicians who stood, and no conductor! The musicians were fully together without a central metronome. Seeing the movement of each performer&amp;rsquo;s body as they swayed and danced to their own playing while passing the harmony between groups of instruments was mesmerizing. I felt like I could visualize the hopping of the melody from violins to violas to cellos. The harpsichord&amp;rsquo;s sound was a beautiful and entirely different sound from the piano I&amp;rsquo;m used to - not quite sure how to describe it. I was fully transported. The flutist was an enchantress embodying the movements from head to toe - body an extension of the instrument, moving in tandem with the violinist. I was so wowed and moved by this performance!! Live instrumental music always does something to me. So energized!!!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-2-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Seeing the form of the essay and writing in general as CARTOGRAPHY. I am mapping out uncharted ideas and editing and creating boundaries to show others.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-31-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Every year I get to have two new years :) and I think that&amp;rsquo;s wonderful.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-30-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Desire paths - &amp;ldquo;the paths that humans prefer, rather than the paths that humans create.&amp;rdquo; Snow is a great way of surfacing the true trails of human movement.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-25-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Silence in the woods and abundant stars. I&amp;rsquo;m so happy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-15-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The people we love are all somewhat figments of our imagination. Probably the most powerful moment in the Three Body Problem series for me, and so far every person I recommend the series to texts me when they reach that section.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-12-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Building worlds with speculative fiction: how, and where, do we cultivate hope? Thrilled for weekly discussions and reading more short sci-fi stories ahh.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-9-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Seeing comfort with silence as a strength.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1-3-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;art papers!! are a thing!!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;12-23-22&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In reflecting on the amazing profs I had this past semester, I&amp;rsquo;m amazed by how passion and knowledge clearly shine through in a person&amp;rsquo;s voice. I don&amp;rsquo;t think Claire (Asian American theater prof) has ever ended up following a syllabus, but just from her conversational teachings I&amp;rsquo;ve learned so much. And even more surprisingly, I&amp;rsquo;ve retained it all with such a deep understanding. I intimately know the state of avant-garde theater in China and the historical plays and their role in politics. She once said that there are people she talks to that make her believe that theater is the most important thing one can do in the world, but that&amp;rsquo;s the way I feel when I&amp;rsquo;m in her class. I want to be able to inspire the same levels of interest. Best prof ever.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;12-18-21&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Somehow my &lt;a href=&#34;https://imageproxy.ifunny.co/crop:x-20,resize:640x,quality:90x75/images/e393def94d970356240fa374948061dccbc0f421374f76c06116d52a6d6483e8_1.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;del&gt;mom&lt;/del&gt; parents&lt;/a&gt; got me the perfect gift without me talking about the depressing weather. A therapy light (so bright!) and What I Know For Sure. Getting a gift that has so much thought and understanding leaves me fuzzy and warm inside.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;12-3-21&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kenliu.name/books/what-is-silkpunk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;silkpunk!&lt;/a&gt; technology as language!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;11-28-21&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Who is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://autotranslucence.wordpress.com/2018/03/30/becoming-a-magician/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;magician you&lt;/a&gt;? The magician me would probably have a book published and an art exhibit. I want to think bigger.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;11-20-21&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Where else except MIT is it the culture to try to find as many hidden vents and crawl spaces to claim. Next up - creating a small art gallery in a vent :)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;11-14-21&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;there&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yume_Wo_Katare&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ramen place for dreams&lt;/a&gt; - it was a gift to share in everyone&amp;rsquo;s dreams and think about mine.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;10-31-21&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the mundane, with someone we love, turns into something special and priceless&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;10-28-21&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;My dreams eerily mirror aspects of my day. Can I predict my dream&amp;rsquo;s contents?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;10-13-21&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What a wonderful feeling to be able to laugh alongside one&amp;rsquo;s fears.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;9-10-21&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vessels for love are these squishy gooey containers. They can stretch and contract. Mine has expanded the past day and I will continue to grow my capacity to hold love.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>explorations</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/explorations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/explorations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;_noticing_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;noticing&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_noticing_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;touch things - the leaves on the bush or the wall of the old building and really feel the interaction&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;take a walk down the street without earbuds and try to notice as many sounds as possible, there is a whole orchestra in traffic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;food meditations - appreciation for the flavors and textures before devouring&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;live life as the main character in a Studio Ghibli movie - romanticize the little things and see the wind dance joyfully through the grass&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;go on a walk - romanticize the little things, see myself as a studio ghibli movie&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;people watch or listen - eavesdropping by a better name. come up with wild stories for each human or object&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;how high is the ceiling right now?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;_living-poetically_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;living poetically&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_living-poetically_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;carry a notebook around and write/doodle all of life’s gifts&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;journal at a park&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I like parks&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;live at parks, bring a blanket and a good book&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;art museums as nourishment of the soul, not mind - focus on the feelings&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;turning spaces into new places&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;sitting at night and feeling the infinite expanse of not being able to see boundaries&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;transform spaces with music and scents&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;_art_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;art&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_art_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;gesture drawings - 30 second sketches to capture the _essence _of a person&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;blind contour drawings - don’t look at the page and release yourself from the shackles of perfection and give yourself permission to notice details&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;make rubbings of objects. touch them. feel them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;zoooooom in&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;self portraits, but make them short and interpretive&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;_writing_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;writing&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_writing_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what did you eat today? write a poem in 10 minutes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what sounds do the objects in your life make? find their rhythms - what do they sound like?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;_moving_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;moving&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_moving_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;interpretive dance - either to the music or picking an object and embodying it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;try to fill up as much room as possible with your body&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;_sound_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;sound&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_sound_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;sit next to the practice rooms and listen to piano as you work&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;sing your poems, say them out loud - what do they sound like?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;_group_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;group&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_group_&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;improv!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;many theater exercises that focus on &lt;del&gt;energy&lt;/del&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;counting up in a group&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;wah!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;group storytelling&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>good content: a list of lists</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/good-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/good-content/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;cool beans &amp;amp; other legumes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Books&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/9809.Invisible_Cities&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Invisible Cities&lt;/a&gt; by Italo Calvino&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Storyworthy-Engage-Persuade-through-Storytelling/dp/1608685489&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Storyworthy&lt;/a&gt; by Matthew Dicks (would recommend audiobook)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Art-Fear-Observations-Rewards-Artmaking/dp/0961454733&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Art &amp;amp; Fear: Observations On the Perils (and Rewards) of Artmaking&lt;/a&gt; by David Bayles, Ted Orland&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Opposite-Loneliness-Essays-Stories/dp/147675361X&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Opposite of Loneliness: Essays and Stories&lt;/a&gt; by Marina Keegan&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://design-justice.pubpub.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Design Justice&lt;/a&gt; by Sasha Costanza-Chock&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Cultish-Language-Fanaticism-Amanda-Montell/dp/0062993151&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cultish: The Language of Fanaticism&lt;/a&gt; by Amanda Montell&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Earth-Were-Briefly-Gorgeous-Novel/dp/0525562028&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;On Earth We&amp;rsquo;re Briefly Gorgeous&lt;/a&gt; by Ocean Vuong&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Metaphors-We-Live-George-Lakoff/dp/0226468011&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Metaphors We Live By&lt;/a&gt; [good skim] by George Lakoff, Mark Johnson&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/What-Artists-Do-Leonard-Koren/dp/0981484662&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;What Artists Do&lt;/a&gt; by Leonard Koren&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Hunger-Memoir-Body-Roxane-Gay/dp/0062362593&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hunger: A Memoir of (My) Body&lt;/a&gt; by Roxane Gay&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Crime-Punishment-Fyodor-Dostoyevsky/dp/0486415872&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Crime and Punishment&lt;/a&gt; by Fyodor Dostoyevsky&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/When-Breath-Becomes-Paul-Kalanithi/dp/081298840X&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;When Breath Becomes Air&lt;/a&gt; by Paul Kalanithi&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Wind-Up-Bird-Chronicle-Novel/dp/0679775439&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Wind-Up Bird Chronicle&lt;/a&gt; by Haruki Murakami&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Exhalation-Stories-Ted-Chiang/dp/1101947888&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Exhalation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Stories-Your-Life-Others-Chiang-ebook/dp/B0048EKOP0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Stories of Your Life and Others&lt;/a&gt; by Ted Chiang&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Axiomatic-Short-Stories-Science-Fiction/dp/1597805408&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Axiomatic&lt;/a&gt; by Greg Egan&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Remembrance-Earths-Past-Three-Body-Trilogy-ebook/dp/B01N198VU5&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Remembrance of Earth&amp;rsquo;s Past&lt;/a&gt; by Cixin Liu&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/All-Light-We-Cannot-See/dp/1501173219&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;All the Light We Cannot See&lt;/a&gt; by Anthony Doerr&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/This-How-You-Lose-Time/dp/1534430997&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This Is How You Lose the Time War&lt;/a&gt; by Amal El-Mohtar, Max Gladstone&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Poetry&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>fundamental questions</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quick questions jotted down as part of our cabin retreat planning activities. What are currently some fundamental questions in your life?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;how can art move a life?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what is the value of attention and observation? how can we be good witnesses?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what does it mean to create something?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;is there a way to increase serendipitous happenings?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what can we learn from others? what must we experience for ourselves?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what objects and ideas are our identities tethered to?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what does it mean to live together?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;how do words help or hinder us?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what other worlds can we build with conceptual metaphors?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;where does permission come from? to feel, express, and do&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what is the balance between observation and sharing?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;when does reflection become too much?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;are there any shoulds? what are they?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what makes a decision hard? what makes a decision good?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;where does technology grant us more agency?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what is creativity? where do computers fit in?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what does digital identity mean?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what is my relationship with technology? is technology necessary?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what stories/narratives have I rewritten about my past? what is the role of memory in identity?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what do I know to be true? what does it mean to be true to me?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what am I afraid of right now?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what do I like about being alone?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;why do I want more? what do I want more of&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what would my life be like if my actions aligned with what I say I value?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
