<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>note on Alicia Guo</title>
    <link>https://axguo.github.io/categories/note/</link>
    <description>Recent content in note on Alicia Guo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://axguo.github.io/categories/note/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>anyone can be a dancer</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/anyone_can_be_a_dancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/anyone_can_be_a_dancer/</guid>
      <description>A friend once told me that there must be something special about human faces that makes them so hard to draw — a certain elusive quality that comes from the ineffable experience of being human. This took me by surprise because I live with an extremely strong belief that it only takes practice, and relatively little at that, to obtain the skills necessary to draw a reasonable human face. It’s true that most attempts at facial features are awful, more resembling elongated emojis than facial features but I think that’s only because we take our faces for granted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I can do it, painfully</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/do-it-painfully/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/do-it-painfully/</guid>
      <description>Something wonderful has changed here. I feel so full of ideas, sending out pitches instead of finished work. Today I reached out to strangers (non-coders) asking if they wanted to collaborate on unspecified projects without knowing if I’d be able to help bring us to reach a shared vision. I felt giddy and sophisticated, like an artist about to graduate from faking it to making it.
A year ago I would have balked at the thought of offering to create something seemingly magical and impossible without a hint of a plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>life&#39;s little gifts 🍃</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/lifesgifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/lifesgifts/</guid>
      <description>from life to me to you :)
 1-29-23  Unconference. Next time I will run a session/conversation.   1-28-23  Have you ever held an idea in your mind and tried to write it without words? I&amp;rsquo;m going further off the abstract deep end with asemic writing.   1-25-23  I NOW HAVE A VINTAGE CORONA FOUR TYPEWRITER. To feel the physicality of my typing like this is incredible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>explorations</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/explorations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/explorations/</guid>
      <description>noticing  touch things - the leaves on the bush or the wall of the old building and really feel the interaction take a walk down the street without earbuds and try to notice as many sounds as possible, there is a whole orchestra in traffic food meditations - appreciation for the flavors and textures before devouring live life as the main character in a Studio Ghibli movie - romanticize the little things and see the wind dance joyfully through the grass go on a walk - romanticize the little things, see myself as a studio ghibli movie people watch or listen - eavesdropping by a better name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>good content: a list of lists</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/good-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/good-content/</guid>
      <description>cool beans &amp;amp; other legumes
Books
 Invisible Cities by Italo Calvino Storyworthy by Matthew Dicks (would recommend audiobook) Art &amp;amp; Fear: Observations On the Perils (and Rewards) of Artmaking by David Bayles, Ted Orland The Opposite of Loneliness: Essays and Stories by Marina Keegan Design Justice by Sasha Costanza-Chock Cultish: The Language of Fanaticism by Amanda Montell On Earth We&amp;rsquo;re Briefly Gorgeous by Ocean Vuong Metaphors We Live By [good skim] by George Lakoff, Mark Johnson What Artists Do by Leonard Koren Hunger: A Memoir of (My) Body by Roxane Gay Crime and Punishment by Fyodor Dostoyevsky When Breath Becomes Air by Paul Kalanithi The Wind-Up Bird Chronicle by Haruki Murakami Exhalation and Stories of Your Life and Others by Ted Chiang Axiomatic by Greg Egan Remembrance of Earth&amp;rsquo;s Past by Cixin Liu All the Light We Cannot See by Anthony Doerr This Is How You Lose the Time War by Amal El-Mohtar, Max Gladstone  Poetry</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fundamental questions</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/questions/</guid>
      <description>Quick questions jotted down as part of our cabin retreat planning activities. What are currently some fundamental questions in your life?
 how can art move a life? what is the value of attention and observation? how can we be good witnesses? what does it mean to create something? is there a way to increase serendipitous happenings? what can we learn from others? what must we experience for ourselves? what objects and ideas are our identities tethered to?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
