<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open on Alicia Guo</title>
    <link>https://axguo.github.io/tags/open/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open on Alicia Guo</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://axguo.github.io/tags/open/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>fundamental questions</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quick questions jotted down as part of our cabin retreat planning activities. What are currently some fundamental questions in your life?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;how can art move a life?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what is the value of attention and observation? how can we be good witnesses?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what does it mean to create something?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;is there a way to increase serendipitous happenings?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what can we learn from others? what must we experience for ourselves?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what objects and ideas are our identities tethered to?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what does it mean to live together?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;how do words help or hinder us?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what other worlds can we build with conceptual metaphors?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;where does permission come from? to feel, express, and do&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what is the balance between observation and sharing?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;when does reflection become too much?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;are there any shoulds? what are they?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what makes a decision hard? what makes a decision good?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;where does technology grant us more agency?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what is creativity? where do computers fit in?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what does digital identity mean?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what is my relationship with technology? is technology necessary?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what stories/narratives have I rewritten about my past? what is the role of memory in identity?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what do I know to be true? what does it mean to be true to me?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what am I afraid of right now?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what do I like about being alone?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;why do I want more? what do I want more of&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what would my life be like if my actions aligned with what I say I value?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
