<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ongoing on Alicia Guo</title>
    <link>https://axguo.github.io/categories/ongoing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ongoing on Alicia Guo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://axguo.github.io/categories/ongoing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Life Plan</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/life_plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/life_plan/</guid>
      <description>View Life Plan in Taper Issue #9 Folders are the perfect place to formulate a plan to accommodate all of the possibilities: how to proceed with a project, a future, a life. What other paths can be imagined? Choosing one folder enters you into a new realm, closed off to the other branches and revealing new directions. Can a life be planned out in your file explorer? Current work is on streamlining the creation process and including actual files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polanimation</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/polanimations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/polanimations/</guid>
      <description>Part of a research effort guided by Ticha Sethapakdi Polanimation explores how polarizers can be used as a passive display technology. The goal of Polanimation is to develop a design tool and fabrication process that allows users to create animated displays that take advantage of this effect. Can we design displays that are non-intrusive? Advertisements that can be filtered by viewers rather than the owners of the billboards? Polarizers are optical filters that allow only specific wavelengths of light to pass through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chalk of the Day</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/chalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/explorations/chalk/</guid>
      <description> Daily chalk lettering in the Ray and Maria Stata Center. Check out our work on instagram. Coverage by MIT News: Drawing daily doodles: Chalk of the Day brightens MIT    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
