<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Food on Alicia Guo</title>
    <link>https://axguo.github.io/tags/food/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Food on Alicia Guo</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://axguo.github.io/tags/food/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>uneven seasonings</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/notes/uneven_seasoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/notes/uneven_seasoning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been cooking a lot recently and trying to find my way to being a capital C chef, the ones that are able to commune with their ingredients and just know which ones will be compatible and have that intuition for what proportions to include. I’m trying to find the secret sauce. The Food Lab by Kenji López-Alt sits on my shelf largely ignored for now due to my stubborn trial and error mindset wanting to develop this relationship naturally. In short, I’m reinventing the wheel. Maybe most of the reason I haven’t gotten around to the book is it is big and intimidating and I was lazy. But I love watching Food Wars while I cook — it’s an entire anime dedicated to discovering food through exploration, trying and failing and stuffed with so many mouth watering animations that make me sad knowing that real food will never look as appetizing. I’m motivated and inspired to be adventurous with my recipes. I want to make them mine, to cross over into the realm of food as art. The episodes are also full of food science and molecular gastronomy to varying degrees of exaggeration and accuracy where my fact check consists not of google but just just trying the thing. One of the plot-twisting moments comes from using uneven flavors — spreading seasoning in varying areas and concentrations over a smooth uniform distribution — to enhance taste. Each bite becomes a surprise, a shifting dance of unexpected flavors and avoids becoming one dimensional. I haven’t tested this fully - it certainly is true for sauces: drizzling and dipping often taste better than dousing a food in sauce. This also checks out with most of the recipes I’ve read and watched. Salt/oil/seasonings are sprinkled on haphazardly and for many years I wondered why they weren’t mixed or massaged better as to be more uniform. Whenever I would, I’d discover that it clearly did not taste as good.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
