<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reflection on Alicia Guo</title>
    <link>https://axguo.github.io/tags/reflection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reflection on Alicia Guo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://axguo.github.io/tags/reflection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>on daily generation and planting seeds</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dailysketch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/dailysketch/</guid>
      <description>a reflection on a month-ish of daily-ish sketches and the seeds that they nourished - check them out here 🤗
    On what it means to continue creating art1:
 &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;it means leaving some loose thread, some unresolved issue, to carry forward and explore in the next piece&amp;hellip;it means always carrying within you the seed crystal for your next destination.&amp;rdquo;
  The First Seed Sometime around October, I participated with some friends in a coding cypher as part of a collaboration between MIT and Lupe Fiasco where we had the creative freedom to create pretty much anything artistic from a very vague prompt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>what is art but a hope and a question?</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/posts/art/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/posts/art/</guid>
      <description>a loose weaving of thoughts on (my) art and where I find myself in the creative ecosystem
When asking myself why I create art, an incomplete but true answer would be because it’s what I’ve always done. In the moments that I am incapable of stringing together the right words, I turn to art. It’s how I find myself dealing with feelings - both those that I don’t want and those that I would like to preserve and hold close to take with me wherever I go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>what I know to be true [22]</title>
      <link>https://axguo.github.io/other/whatiknow22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 13:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://axguo.github.io/other/whatiknow22/</guid>
      <description>What I know to be true at 22, and possibly not at 23.
What I know changes with each of the lives that I live.
I think it&amp;rsquo;d be fun to do one of these every year :)
  What I know to be true is that attention and observation are what make life meaningful. I want to witness the world and the people in it. Attending to myself, to friends, to nature, to strangers has never been more pressing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
